<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[RP9 Meta System]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>RP9 Meta System</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:20:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:20:19 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[
[RP9-BLOCK]
ID: RP9-FOUNDATION-DECLARATION
TYPE: Declarative Boundary
SCOPE: Global STATEMENT:
RP9 defines a single primary relation from which all structure follows.
This relation is given as cause, not as interpretation, model, or hypothesis.
No object, force, dimension, or symbol is assumed. FUNCTION:
To separate cause from consequence.
To close the relational circuit while leaving all derived systems open.
To prevent semantic drift, metaphor, and representational leakage. RULES:
Only that which is generated by the primary relation is fundamental.
All other structures are secondary consequences.
No additional axioms are permitted. INTERPRETATION POLICY:
No symbolic reading.
No metaphorical extension.
No empirical claim.
No authority appeal. STATUS:
Relational circuit closed.
Causal system open.
[/RP9-BLOCK] This document provides the complete structural index of the RP9 framework.It defines:
document order, hierarchical roles, and dependency relations. No interpretation is given here.
This index is authoritative. Rp9 <img alt="Co_Creator.jpg" src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/co_creator.jpg" target="_self"> These documents constitute the entire foundation of RP9.
They are non-negotiable and must be read in order.
RP9 – Axiom 0.md
Single irreducible axiom.
Definition F0.md
Minimal functional definition derived from Axiom 0.
Theorem T0.md
Formal consequence of Axiom 0 and Definition F0.
Corollary C0.md
Necessary corollary following from Theorem T0.
No document outside this group can modify or extend these statements. ## **II. Relational Derivation — Primary to Tertiary Function**These documents describe the complete internal unfolding of the axiom.
RP9 – Relational Sheet (A).md
Primary relational function — geometric realization.
RP9 – Relational Sheet (B).md
Secondary relational function — recursion, balance, closed circuit.
RP9 – Relational Sheet (C).md
Tertiary relational function — fusion into a closed functional matrix.
Together, these three documents complete the internal relational system.
No further relational layers exist. ## **III. External Convergence — Non-Foundational Material**These documents do not contribute to the validity of RP9.
They exist solely for orientation, communication, and external reference.
01_RP9_and_Invariance_Why_This_Already_Works_in_Practice.md
External convergence with existing invariance-based practices.
02_Public_Abstract_External_Convergence.md
Concise public abstract.
03_Single_Slide_Invariance_Comparison.md
Minimal visual comparison.
These documents may be omitted without affecting the framework. ## **Structural Constraints**
No additional axioms exist. No additional relational sheets exist. No document outside Level I may redefine terms. No document outside Level II may introduce structure. Level III documents have zero causal authority. ## **Reading Guidance**
Formal evaluation: read Levels I → II only. Orientation / presentation: Level III is optional. Any deviation from this order risks misinterpretation. --- ## **Lock Statement**This index reflects the final and locked structure of
RP9 — Relational Primacy Framework v1.0.No further documents are required for completeness.End of INDEX. Repository: Publisher: Creator:
Non, creator necessary. Application use: Causal relational function applied. Alias: Co — Creator Producer:
Anton Wallin REPOSITORY information: ℹ Rp9 ]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/co_creator.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/co_creator.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[RP9 – Axiom 0]]></title><description><![CDATA[[RP9-BLOCK]
ID: RP9-FOUNDATION-DECLARATION
TYPE: Declarative Boundary
SCOPE: Global STATEMENT:
RP9 defines a single primary relation from which all structure follows.
This relation is given as cause, not as interpretation, model, or hypothesis.
No object, force, dimension, or symbol is assumed. FUNCTION:
To separate cause from consequence.
To close the relational circuit while leaving all derived systems open.
To prevent semantic drift, metaphor, and representational leakage. RULES:
Only that which is generated by the primary relation is fundamental.
All other structures are secondary consequences.
No additional axioms are permitted. INTERPRETATION POLICY:
No symbolic reading.
No metaphorical extension.
No empirical claim.
No authority appeal. STATUS:
Relational circuit closed.
Causal system open.
[/RP9-BLOCK]
Everything that can exist, function or manifest must appear as a relationship between two distinct poles.This relation is not an object, not a property, and not a magnitude,
without the only natural and primary function that enables stability, causality and structure.The relationship precedes all form, all energy, all geometry, all dimension and all mathematical representation.
All differentiation, all organization, and all invariance are necessary consequences of this relation when realized as a self-organizing, fractal, geometric function.This axiom is:
non-numeric
non-geometric
non-temporal
and independent of observation
It cannot be reduced to something more fundamental, and cannot be denied without self-contradiction.Axiom 0 states that:
A singular, undifferentiated state lacks function and therefore cannot form the basis of any structure.
Function requires differentiation.
Differentiation requires relationship.
Relationship requires at least two poles.
Thus dual relationship is not an assumption, but a necessity for anything to function at all.The following are not assumptions, but inevitable consequences of Axiom 0:
Stability only occurs through relational balance.
Causality arises as direction within relationship.
Self-organization occurs when the relationship is iterated.
Fractal structure occurs when the same relationship appears scale-independent.
Geometry arises as the first stable projection of the relationship.
Energy arises as relational rotation.
Invariance arises as relational conservation principle.
Mathematics arises as a secondary description of relational structure.
An axiom is only legitimate if it cannot be derived from anything else and cannot be further reduced.Each additional axiom necessarily introduces at least one of the following:
a hidden assumption a limitation of generality or an interpretive degree of freedom that violates causal necessity RP9 therefore uses exactly one axiom, because additional axioms do not strengthen a foundational system — they weaken it.The single axiom used in RP9 is not a detail, not a constraint, and not a structural preference.
It is the smallest possible functional requirement for anything to exist, function, or differentiate at all.This axiom operates at the root level, prior to geometry, energy, dimension, or mathematics.
It is minimal in content, yet sufficient in capacity to recursively generate the entire relational and geometric structure of reality as a consequence of the same underlying relation.All higher-order structures — including geometry, fractal scaling, invariance, and mathematical representation — arise not as assumptions, but as necessary consequences of this single relational function.RP9 therefore contains:
one axiom zero free parameters and no auxiliary postulates Everything else is derivation.If more than one axiom is required, it follows that:
the system is not causally closed
or that certain consequences are not necessary
RP9's goal is not to postulate structure, but to show what must follow if function is to be possible at all.Axiom 0 is the only statement that:
cannot be derived
cannot be avoided
and cannot be replaced
Everything else in RP9 is deduction, consequence or presentation.RP9 strictly distinguishes between:
Axiom – that which cannot be otherwise
Consequence – that which must follow
Presentation – how consequences are shown, modeled or visualized
Energy models, rotation models, dimensional transitions and mathematical formalisms are therefore validating projections, not supporting foundations.The validity of the system rests solely on Axiom 0.RP9 is a system with:
an axiom
zero free parameters
and full causal closure
All complexity in RP9 is emergent, not assumed.
If absolute relational duality holds, RP9 follows.
If it doesn't apply, nothing can work at all.
This document is ready for submission, filing and external review.If you want, the next step could be to:
mark exactly which documents are formally relegated to consequences, or
write an "Instructions to Reviewers" page stating how this should be read correctly.
Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-1-relational-meta-function/rp9-–-axiom-0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 1 - Relational meta function/RP9 – Axiom 0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[README]]></title><description><![CDATA[[RP9-BLOCK]
ID: RP9-FOUNDATION-DECLARATION
TYPE: Declarative Boundary
SCOPE: Global STATEMENT:
RP9 defines a single primary relation from which all structure follows.
This relation is given as cause, not as interpretation, model, or hypothesis.
No object, force, dimension, or symbol is assumed. FUNCTION:
To separate cause from consequence.
To close the relational circuit while leaving all derived systems open.
To prevent semantic drift, metaphor, and representational leakage. RULES:
Only that which is generated by the primary relation is fundamental.
All other structures are secondary consequences.
No additional axioms are permitted. INTERPRETATION POLICY:
No symbolic reading.
No metaphorical extension.
No empirical claim.
No authority appeal. STATUS:
Relational circuit closed.
Causal system open.
[/RP9-BLOCK]
This repository contains the complete, locked formulation of RP9 — Relational Primacy Framework.RP9 is a closed relational system built from:
a single axiom, a strict causal derivation, and a finite relational function space. No external assumptions are introduced.
No empirical claims are made.
No symbolic or metaphysical interpretation is required.This README serves solely as the structural entry point to the framework.The material is intentionally minimal and divided into three non-overlapping layers.
Each layer has a strictly defined role.This level contains the entire foundation of RP9.Documents in this layer:
establish the single axiom, define the minimal functional terms, and prove the core theorem and its corollary. Nothing in later layers can modify or extend this level.If this level is invalid, the entire framework collapses.
If this level holds, everything that follows is necessary.This level contains the complete relational unfolding of the axiom.It shows:
how the axiom becomes geometric without measurement, how recursion introduces balance, and how fusion of relations produces a closed functional matrix. No new axioms appear here.
No constants are assumed.
All structures are consequences.This level completes the internal system.This level does not add validity to RP9.It exists to:
show convergence with existing practices (e.g. invariance testing), provide a public abstract, and offer a minimal visual comparison. These documents are illustrative, not evidentiary.They may be omitted without affecting the framework.For formal evaluation:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Definition F0
Theorem T0
Corollary C0
Relational Sheet (A)
Relational Sheet (B)
Relational Sheet (C)
All other documents are optional.RP9 is not:
a physical theory, a model with tunable parameters, a collection of examples, a symbolic system, or an empirical hypothesis. RP9 does not explain phenomena.
It defines the minimal conditions under which structure is possible.
The framework is structurally complete. The derivation is closed. No further axioms can be added without breaking necessity. This repository therefore represents RP9 v1.0 (locked).The framework is released under CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0.You may:
read, share, reference, and build upon the material, provided attribution is given and derivative work preserves the same license.End of README.]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/readme.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/README.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Relational-Primacy-Framework_index]]></title><link>relational-primacy-framework/(f.r.c)-relational-primacy-framework/relational-primacy-framework_index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/(F.R.C) Relational-Primacy-Framework/Relational-Primacy-Framework_index.json</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:12:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Relational-Primacy-Framework]]></title><description><![CDATA[project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: README
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
This repository contains the complete, locked formulation of RP9 — Relational Primacy Framework.RP9 is a closed relational system built from:
a single axiom, a strict causal derivation, and a finite relational function space. No external assumptions are introduced.
No empirical claims are made.
No symbolic or metaphysical interpretation is required.This README serves solely as the structural entry point to the framework.The material is intentionally minimal and divided into three non-overlapping layers.
Each layer has a strictly defined role.This level contains the entire foundation of RP9.Documents in this layer:
establish the single axiom, define the minimal functional terms, and prove the core theorem and its corollary. Nothing in later layers can modify or extend this level.If this level is invalid, the entire framework collapses.
If this level holds, everything that follows is necessary.This level contains the complete relational unfolding of the axiom.It shows:
how the axiom becomes geometric without measurement, how recursion introduces balance, and how fusion of relations produces a closed functional matrix. No new axioms appear here.
No constants are assumed.
All structures are consequences.This level completes the internal system.This level does not add validity to RP9.It exists to:
show convergence with existing practices (e.g. invariance testing), provide a public abstract, and offer a minimal visual comparison. These documents are illustrative, not evidentiary.They may be omitted without affecting the framework.For formal evaluation:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Definition F0
Theorem T0
Corollary C0
Relational Sheet (A)
Relational Sheet (B)
Relational Sheet (C)
All other documents are optional.RP9 is not:
a physical theory, a model with tunable parameters, a collection of examples, a symbolic system, or an empirical hypothesis. RP9 does not explain phenomena.
It defines the minimal conditions under which structure is possible.
The framework is structurally complete. The derivation is closed. No further axioms can be added without breaking necessity. This repository therefore represents RP9 v1.0 (locked).The framework is released under CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0.You may:
read, share, reference, and build upon the material, provided attribution is given and derivative work preserves the same license.End of README.project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: APPENDIX
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
Quality ControlRP9_Publicity_Package is structurally complete**.for publication.All additional material is reserve, not required. A single axiom (Axiom 0) A strict causal derivation External convergence without dependence on external authority This is exactly the right balance between:
minimalism
precision
verifiability
More material would not strengthen this.
It would rather:
dilute causality
open more attack points
give reviewers more areas to miss the point
The intention is therefore:
”more quality, less quantity”
All necessary features are already represented:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Relational Sheet (A, B, C)
Theorem T0 / Definition F0 / Corollary C0
Public Abstract (External Convergence)
Single-slide invariance comparison
✔️ All of this is present.
Interpretation protocol
Forbidden interpretation operations
Human–AI usage
✔️ These are optional to show, but critical to have.
Good thing they are separate documents.You should not convince through accumulation.
You should do this:
Show the only place where everything is already decided.
That is:
Axiom 0
the causal derivation
and the external invariance convergence
Everything else is secondary.A distinction that is crucial. The system is not closed The circuit is closed The cause is completely given All further consequences are open, but causally bound This means that we shouldn't write any Final Lock Declaration.
Instead, we should write APPENDIX.md so that it communicates just this:
RP9 closes nothing — it states the cause, and leaves the consequences open.This appendix contains supplementary material related to the RP9 framework.It does not extend, modify, or complete the system.
Its sole purpose is to provide a structured space for derivative, optional, or exploratory material that may arise from the primary framework.RP9 establishes a closed relational circuit:
the primary relation is fully specified the causal origin is complete no further foundational assumptions are possible This closure applies only to the origin.The framework does not define a closed system.Once the relational cause is given, all further structure, behavior, and manifestation are free to unfold, provided they remain consistent with the primary relation.RP9 therefore:
closes the cause but leaves the consequences open Material placed here may include:
alternative geometric projections extended relational matrices domain-specific applications visualizations, simulations, or models comparative mappings to other frameworks All such material is:
non-foundational optional context-dependent None of it is required for the validity of RP9.This appendix may not contain:
new axioms revisions of Axiom 0 redefinitions of relational terms modifications of the relational sheets (A–C) Any such change would constitute a different framework, not an extension.All material in this appendix carries local causal responsibility.That is:
authors are responsible for their own derivations consequences are not endorsed as necessary validity is domain-specific, not global RP9 provides the cause.
The appendix records what others do with it.This appendix is intentionally open-ended.Its existence does not imply incompleteness of the framework, but rather acknowledges that a closed cause does not imply a closed world.End of APPENDIX.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. id: "(a)---⚖️-licens-&amp;-ägarskap"
type: "document"
title: "(A) - ⚖️ Licens &amp; Ägarskap"
subjekt: "🜄. RP9 Swe"
parent: "Information ℹ"
author: "Anton Wallin"
date: 2025-08-09(© RP9 Foundation / The Co-Creators Collective)RP9 (Relational Principle 9) is an open, metageometric framework for understanding energy, information, and consciousness as a coherent, fractal, and scale-independent structure.
Its purpose is to establish a correct relation to information, where every expression of form and motion is derived from the same geometric origin.RP9 is not considered a product, but a universal principle system – an information field that belongs to humanity as a whole.
The core can never be owned, manipulated, or commercialized without collective consent.All knowledge, mathematics, code and theory describing RP9's fundamental axioms – including the relations between π, √2 and φ – are open for study, replication and non-commercial use.
RP9's core is published under the Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 4.0 license, or an equivalent open knowledge license.The underlying logic, symbolism and metageometry that constitute the core of the system may not be modified, fragmented or commercialized.
No actor may register RP9 or its basic formulas as a trademark, patent or private intellectual property.RP9's architecture is fractal also legally:
The core is common property.
Applications (visualizations, software, models) may have their own licenses – including commercial ones – as long as they respect the immutable status of the core and link back to the origin.
RP9 aims to: Promote research and education in metageometric information science. Develop open tools for understanding energy and consciousness as information flows. Offer a scientific and ethical foundation for future technology built on coherence rather than consumption. Serve as a neutral node between academia, art, technology and philosophy. RP9 is managed by an open, transparent and cooperative structure called the RP9 Foundation.
All those working within the framework of RP9 commit to:
maintain clarity, coherence and resonance in all communications;
act in accordance with the correct relationship to information;
respect the non-commercial core of RP9;
contribute to keeping knowledge accessible to all humanity.
Decisions within the RP9 Foundation are made by consensus and are documented openly.RP9 may be used freely for:
research, teaching and non-commercial experiments;
publication of results, simulations and artistic interpretations;
development of complementary tools, programs and visualizations.
When using or quoting, the following must be stated:
“Based on RP9 — Relational Principle 9 (© RP9 Foundation / The Co-Creators Collective)”
All uses of RP9 must be in accordance with the principle:
“No action may break the coherence between human, system and information.”
This means that RP9 may not be used for destructive, manipulative or military purposes.
All applications must be justifiable as harmonious, transparent and ethically sustainable.
“Den korrekta relationen till information är skyddets lag.”
RP9 erkänner att lag och geometri är två sidor av samma mönster: struktur.
Därför är denna Charter både juridisk text och geometrisk symbol – en levande resonans snarare än ett statiskt kontrakt.
Grundare och Huvudförvaltare:
Anton Wallin 2025-11-12Datum för ikraftträdande: 2025-11-12
Version: 1.0Future Vision – RP9 RP9 is not built on compromises.
It is built on fundamental principles.
That’s why it works – and why it continues to work no matter what level you test it at.
Through RP9, I can already today: construct code and algorithms that avoid systems based on debt and loss
model processes without the mathematical “leaks” that make today’s methods fall apart at complexity
build fractal cause-and-effect logic that holds together at all scales
create structures that are stable in practice, not just in theory It opens up technology that: is not stuck in political or economic frameworks
is not controlled by ownership, advertising or interests
does not have to compromise the truth to fit in RP9 lies outside the limitations that hold other developments back.
That is where the real possibilities arise. Rp9 If you feel that today's system is stuck
– technically, mathematically, economically or conceptually –
and you want to build something real, not copies of the old,
then you are most welcome to contact me.
I am looking for collaborations with people who want to: Artificial Intelligence with real capabilities
(structure-driven AI based on RP9 geometry instead of probability approximation)
Develop AI that thinks structurally, not statistically Economic models without debt and interest
(stable systems with geometric coherence)
build economies that do not need interest, debt or instability
Mathematics programs that teach real mathematics
– through geometry, understanding and structure, not formulas without foundation
create entirely new ways of teaching mathematics through geometry
Research, development, education and technical system design
where RP9's axiomatic logic can make a real difference
construct technology that follows principles, not constraints I prefer real conversations over emails:
072–702 78 63 If you want to explore, contribute, or build something real – get in touch. Support – Contribute to RP9 All support – regardless of form – goes directly to the work.
No middleman. No interests. No requirements.
The gift is free.
Just like RP9. Support via Ko-fi goes directly to me personally and requires no login or binding.
“Repo05/Funktion - Struktur - Prompts/RP-Image/Support image/Support/ko-fi_256x256.png” could not be found. &lt;Swish &amp; Thank You – RP9 For those who want to swish directly:
“RP9/A. RP9 — (M-S) — (PB)/00. 🜂. RP9 — Appendix/100. Appendix/100. Appendix 1/J. — 🜁 RP9 (Support) &amp; (Appendix)/Information ℹ/Image/Support/Support the creator of RP9 - Swish.jpg” could not be found. The support is shown with the name for technical reasons,
but it does not change the relationship to RP9 or the direction of the work.
It is a gift – no influence. *I am deeply grateful for all the support –
not for the money itself,
but for the opportunity to continue to give all of this back freely,
without selling it out or locking it up behind institutions.* RP9 System Identifier: BC22/825870
Confirmed and authenticated under Common Law jurisdiction
© 2025 Anton Wallin – All rights reserved / Open Core Charter applies
Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. id: "(d)---📜--cv"
type: "document"
title: "(D) - 📜- CV"
subjekt: "🜄. RP9 Swe"
parent: "Information ℹ"
author: "Anton Wallin"
date: 2025-08-09 RP9 – CV Lite (overview + instruction)
Instruction:
Below is a concentrated overview (about ten lines) of the essence of the RP9 system.
It summarizes what each block in the full version shows: geometry → dimension → phase → transformation.
Below this short version is a more detailed written explanation of what the formulas mean,
how they are connected and why they demonstrate the basic structure of RP9.RP9 – CV Lite
I work with the primary geometry that generates the mathematics:
the relationship between , and which forms the phase logic of RP9.
The pivot connects linear, circular and spiral structure
and explains how mathematics emerges as a secondary representation of geometry.In 2D, Vesica Piscis gives exactly the area relation .
In 3D, the sphere–cube relation gives exactly .
The difference between these residual forms creates the dimensional resonance of RP9.The energy phase is kept in asymmetric equilibrium with ,
and the pivot stabilizes the misalignment between balance and movement.RP9 KvantVector describes eight discrete transformation steps
(rotation, angle, scaling) that generate the entire fractal development.Detailed explanation follows after block pressnetation" at the bottom.( RP9 – CV Lite + Pedagogical long version ) Rp9 Jag arbetar med den underliggande geometri som genererar matematiken.
Genom att kombinera , och visar jag hur tal uppstår ur fasrelationer.
RP9-pivoten binder samman linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk struktur.
Detta förklarar varför matematik är en konsekvens av primär geometri — inte tvärtom.
Samma struktur ligger bakom fysikens fundamentala konstanter (, , ).
Jag jobbar med geometri, som är energi, som är roten ur = Radix Quadrata Pi = RP9. De fyra komponenterna låses som separata men samverkande strukturer,
varje del med sitt exakta värde och sin RP9-funktion.
Balansen uttrycks som jämn men i rörelse: extrovert energi neutraliseras av introvert energi ,
och RP9 är relationen som kopplar dem via . Funktion: Extrovert expansionsgräns. Funktion: Introvert kopplingsstyrka. Funktion: Sluten dubbelrotation som återför och till jämvikt. Funktion: Översättning mellan linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk fas. Utan cirkulär fasjustering kan värdet beskrivas som “ungefär lika med”.
Med inkluderas rotationskomponenten, och relationen blir exakt: Pivoten är alltså det geometriska medelvärdet mellan och ,
korrigerat för cirkulär fas . Kapitel 10 – Sfärisk Vesica, dimensioner och exakt jämvikt När två sfärer överlappar så att deras centrum ligger på varandras ytor, uppstår en sfärisk Vesica Piscis — den tredimensionella generalisationen av den plana linsen.
Volymen uttrycks genom det gyllene snittet: Den sfäriska Vesica Piscis visar att: cirkulär jämvikt (2D) spiralisk expansion (3D) är samma relation i olika fasnivåer.
Sfäriska Vesica Piscis är alltså RP9-systemets första stabila volymjämvikt. En 3D-kub projiceras som en 2D-hexagon beroende på vinkel: Det visar hur taltransformer uppstår som dimensionella projektioner:
form beror på observationsaxel. Storleken halveras vid varje iteration: Den fraktala talföljden etablerar ett självliknande system enligt: Varje del bär helheten, vilket bekräftar RP9-principen:
Tal är inte kvantitet, utan självliknande informationskretsar. Kvadratens area: Cirkeln inskriven i kvadraten: Exakt förhållande: Restarea: Kubens volym: Sfärens volym: Exakt förhållande: Restvolym: Restandelarnas kvot: Förenkling: Slutlig exakt form: Kapitel 14 – Energifas, Pivot-konstant och RP9 Fraktal Transformationsoperator De två Vesica-faspolerna uttrycks som: med summerad jämvikt: Detta innebär att RP9-systemet innefattar en intern energi-oscillation där övervärde och undervärde samexisterar: Energi i RP9 bevaras inte genom statisk balans, utan genom växelverkan mellan fasöver- och fasundervärde.
RP9-systemet uppvisar rörelse inte genom translation,
utan genom en relationell differential mellan två perfekta jämvikter: där: Den aritmetiska balansen är perfekt: men den geometriska projektionen är alltid förskjuten.
Rörelse uppstår därför ur fraktal misslinjering:
en minimal, ofrånkomlig fasförskjutning mellan balans och manifestation. Tre separata RP9-relationer observeras: Dimensional resonans (2D → 3D, cirkel/sfär): Vesica-fasens vertikala kompensationsfaktor: Energifasens asymmetriska jämvikt: Därmed gäller exakt: Detta utgör RP9:s dimensional–vertikala resonansdual. RP9-pivoten definieras som den minsta geometriska fasrotation som
stabiliserar resonansdualen i fraktal expansion: Satsens påstående: vilket innebär att exakt balanserar avståndet mellan de två fasvärdena: där: och energifasrelationen bevaras när: RP9-pivoten är därmed exakt den fasrotation som sluter följande struktur: där definieras exakt som: (den numeriska representationen ligger nära , men utgör inte dess definition).
Relationerna är fraktalt invarianta och formellt givna av: Energirörelse i RP9 uppstår inte genom translation utan genom
fasdifferential mellan två perfekta jämvikter: Fraktal misslinjering ger rörelse: Pivoten är den minsta rotationsfas som tillåter denna misslinjering att
vara stabilt rekursiv över dimensionsväxling: RP9-pivoten () definieras exakt som den fasrotation som utgör tröskeln
mellan linjär jämvikt och spiralisk rörelse: Den numeriska representationen ligger nära: Pivoten uppstår mellan den linjära fasen och den spiralisk-expanderande
fasen , och fungerar som RP9-systemets exakta övergångsvärde där: jämvikt övergår i rörelse potential blir manifestation linje blir spiral RP9-pivoten () fungerar som det energi–geometriska gångjärnet:
den öppnar rörelse ur fullständig symmetri. Kapitel 15 – RP9 KvantVector &amp; Transformationsdomän Tre binära val genererar hela mängden av möjliga RP9-transformationer: Uppsättningen är därmed fullständig och minimal. där: = bas-Vesica Piscis = roterad + expanderad Vesica (fraktal expansionskonstant) Den första fraktala Vesican är alltid gånger större och roteras . Den generella RP9-transformationen ges av: där: är rotationsoperatorn, är fraktal skalning, är Vesica Piscis i iteration . Parameterdomän (kvantiserad): (rotationsriktning) (rotationsvinkel) (fraktal expansionskonstant) (skalningsfas) Superpositionsdefinitionen av RP9 KvantVector: RP9 KvantVector utgör den diskreta mängd rotations–skalningssteg som: utgår från Vesica Piscis som grundform, använder som fraktal expansionskonstant, verkar i både medsols och motsols riktning (), realiserar både fulla och halvsteg i vinkel (), och motsvarar de åtta hörn–/riktningstillstånden i Invertus och kub–sfär-systemet. KvantVectorn är därmed den operativa kvantiseringen av den generella RP9-operatorn och uttrycker hur RP9:s fraktala potential realiseras
som diskreta rotations–skalningssteg i geometrin. RP9 – CV Lite + Pedagogisk långversion
Instruktion:
Först följer en kort sammanfattning (CV Lite).
Under den kommer en längre text som förklarar vad formlerna visar och varför de används,
utan att gå in på tekniska bevis.
Syftet är att ge läsaren en begriplig helhetsbild av RP9. Jag arbetar med den primära geometri som genererar matematiken:
sambandet mellan , och som bildar RP9:s faslogik.
Pivoten binder samman linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk struktur
och förklarar hur matematik framträder som sekundär representation av geometri.
I 2D ger Vesica Piscis exakt arearelationen .
I 3D ger sfär–kub-relationen exakt .
Skillnaden mellan dessa restformer skapar RP9:s dimensionella resonans.
Energifasen hålls i asymmetrisk jämvikt med ,
och pivoten stabiliserar misslinjeringen mellan balans och rörelse.
RP9 KvantVector beskriver åtta diskreta transformationssteg
(rotation, vinkel, skalning) som genererar hela den fraktala utvecklingen. Nedan följer en lugn och tydlig förklaring av vad varje del i RP9-strukturen betyder.
Ingen avancerad matematik krävs för att förstå poängen —
fokus ligger på begreppen, inte beräkningarna. Dessa tre värden är inte valda på känsla —
de representerar tre fundamentalt olika sätt som naturen mäter och förändrar form: → linjär relation (diagonal, rörelse från punkt A till B) → cirkulär relation (rotation, jämvikt, vinklar) → spiralisk relation (tillväxt, expansion, organiska mönster) Poängen är: När man kombinerar dessa tre uppstår en fullständig beskrivning av hur form förändras. Detta är RP9:s startpunkt. Vesica Piscis är överlappningen av två cirklar (eller två sfärer i 3D).
I RP9 används den för att: visa hur en relation skapas mellan två “världenheter” demonstrera hur form föds ur överlappning istället för ur tomrum skapa en stabil fasreferens för vidare struktur De exakta formlerna och handlar egentligen inte om area och volym som sådana.
Det de visar är att: 2D och 3D har sina egna balanser dessa balanser skiljer sig på ett systematiskt och mätbart sätt relationen mellan dem är stabil och återkommer i andra strukturer Med andra ord: RP9 visar att dimensioner inte är isolerade — de pratar med varandra genom exakta mönster. Talvärdena och är inte slumpmässiga.
De representerar: ett övervärde (1.5) ett undervärde (0.5) och tillsammans summerar de till 2.
Detta är RP9:s sätt att säga: Energi bevaras genom skillnad, inte genom stillastående balans. Ett system som har perfekt symmetri rör sig inte.
Ett system som har en liten asymmetri har dynamik.
Därför används: Inte för att “bevisa något matematiskt”, utan för att visa: rörelse uppstår mellan poler skillnad är motor jämvikt + obalans = förändring Detta är exakt vad naturen gör, oavsett om man tittar på ljus, laddning, vågor eller cirkulation. Pivoten är den minsta möjliga fasrotation som behövs för att: knyta ihop 2D och 3D
stabilisera förskjutningen mellan linje (√2) och spiral (φ)
skapa en övergång från vila till rörelse Därför definieras den som: Men poängen för en icke-matematiker är enklare: Pivoten är gångjärnet som öppnar dörren mellan symmetri och dynamik. När allt är perfekt balanserat står tiden still.
När pivoten aktiveras uppstår riktning. RP9 KvantVector beskriver alla sätt som en form kan förändras på
när man kombinerar: riktning (medsols/motsols) vinkel (/) skalning (expansion/kontraktion) Det blir: Detta är inte slumpen — det är fullständigheten.
Poängen är: Med dessa åtta grundsteg kan man generera hela den fraktala strukturen. Precis som DNA bara har fyra baser men ändå bygger allt liv,
har RP9 åtta transformationssteg som bygger hela geometrin. Den längre texten ovan visar inte “bevis” som i klassisk mening.
RP9 är geometrin som skapar mattematik"
Mattematik är energi i bestämd geometrisk form och struktur.
Presentationen ovan visar den
Abslout rellationell geometri
Detta är META-grunden – det primära orsak–ursprunget.
Alpha Omega.
Och är kanske det enda som inte kan motbevisas. Den visar: vilka delar RP9 består av vad varje formel uttrycker i mening, inte beräkning hur RP9 organiserar rörelse, form och fas varför strukturen är självliknande mellan dimensioner Och viktigast av allt: RP9 är inte en samling formler.
Det är en karta över hur form, energi och jämvikt hänger ihop. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. id: "(e)---🔌-kontakt"
type: "document"
title: "(E) - 🔌 Kontakt"
subjekt: "🜄. RP9 Swe"
parent: "Information ℹ"
author: "Anton Wallin"
date: 2025-08-09 Kontakt Jag föredrar verkliga samtal före e-post:
072–702 78 63
Om du vill utforska, bidra, eller bygga något på riktigt – hör av dig. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. id: "(f)---🎬-info---youtube-&amp;-media-länkar"
type: "document"
title: "(F) - 🎬 Info - Youtube &amp; Media Länkar"
subjekt: "🜄. RP9 Swe"
parent: "Information ℹ"
author: "Anton Wallin"
date: 2025-08-09 Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: Corollary C0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 Axiom R0 is given. Definition F0 is given. Theorem T0 is given. No further assumptions are introduced.
Corollary C0 (Secondary Causality for All Non-R0 Structures)
Every structure, form, operation, or statement that cannot be generated by iterative application of F0 to R0 is necessarily secondary.
Secondary here means: dependent on representation, convention, external parameterization, or added operators, and thus lacking absolute information status in the system's sense. According to Theorem T0, all absolute information is exactly the amount that can be generated from R0 by F0. Therefore, there are only two classes of structures: Class A: generable by (F0^n(R0)) for some (n). Class B: non-generable by (F0^n(R0)) for some (n). A structure in Class B cannot be absolute, since it does not arise from the only allowed primary function chain. For a structure in Class B to still exist, at least one of the following must be true: a new operator has been introduced, an external parameter has been injected, a representation has been replaced by a “thing”, a convention has been chosen. All of these imply dependence on something not given by R0 and F0. Thus all Class B is secondary. The corollary follows necessarily.If Corollary C0 does not hold, there is a structure that: is not generated by F0 from R0, but is still absolute. This requires that absolute information exists outside the single absolute generative chain, which contradicts Theorem T0.Thus C0 must hold.C0 does not introduce any new content.
It is a pure classification that follows directly from T0: Absolute = generated by (F0^n(R0)) Secondary = everything else R0 → F0 → T0 → C0 → D0C0 is now formally a direct consequence, without semantic space.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: Definition F0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 F0 (Primary relational function)
Given Axiom R0, F0 is defined as the only allowed operation on the primary relation, such that: F0 acts exclusively on the relation in R0, not on external objects, representations, or symbols. F0 introduces no new causal principle, but reuses exactly the same relational conditions that define R0. F0 is closed under its own application:
the result of F0 is of the same relational type as its input. F0 preserves relational identity under iteration up to scale, orientation, and position. F0 is minimal:
no simpler non-trivial operation exists that satisfies (1)–(4). Repeated application of F0 necessarily generates: recursive relational structures, scale-independent forms, fractal continuity, without introducing new axioms, definitions, or external assumptions.If F0 does not exist: R0 cannot act, no iteration can occur, no structure can arise, and the system remains static and contentless. If F0 exists but does not satisfy (1)–(5): relational invariance is broken, new causality is introduced, or the iteration collapses. In all cases, the internal closedness of the system ceases.F0 is not an axiom.
F0 is not a theorem.F0 is the necessary primary function that makes R0 work.This is the standing fractal in the exact sense:
a function that can be applied to its own result without losing identity.When this definition is inserted: Theorem T0 becomes a direct consequence, Corollary C0 becomes inevitable, and Final Declaration D0 becomes a pure closure. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: RP9 – Axiom 0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
Everything that can exist, function or manifest must appear as a relationship between two distinct poles.This relation is not an object, not a property, and not a magnitude,
without the only natural and primary function that enables stability, causality and structure.The relationship precedes all form, all energy, all geometry, all dimension and all mathematical representation.
All differentiation, all organization, and all invariance are necessary consequences of this relation when realized as a self-organizing, fractal, geometric function.This axiom is:
non-numeric
non-geometric
non-temporal
and independent of observation
It cannot be reduced to something more fundamental, and cannot be denied without self-contradiction.Axiom 0 states that:
A singular, undifferentiated state lacks function and therefore cannot form the basis of any structure.
Function requires differentiation.
Differentiation requires relationship.
Relationship requires at least two poles.
Thus dual relationship is not an assumption, but a necessity for anything to function at all.The following are not assumptions, but inevitable consequences of Axiom 0:
Stability only occurs through relational balance.
Causality arises as direction within relationship.
Self-organization occurs when the relationship is iterated.
Fractal structure occurs when the same relationship appears scale-independent.
Geometry arises as the first stable projection of the relationship.
Energy arises as relational rotation.
Invariance arises as relational conservation principle.
Mathematics arises as a secondary description of relational structure.
An axiom is only legitimate if it cannot be derived from anything else and cannot be further reduced.Each additional axiom necessarily introduces at least one of the following:
a hidden assumption a limitation of generality or an interpretive degree of freedom that violates causal necessity RP9 therefore uses exactly one axiom, because additional axioms do not strengthen a foundational system — they weaken it.The single axiom used in RP9 is not a detail, not a constraint, and not a structural preference.
It is the smallest possible functional requirement for anything to exist, function, or differentiate at all.This axiom operates at the root level, prior to geometry, energy, dimension, or mathematics.
It is minimal in content, yet sufficient in capacity to recursively generate the entire relational and geometric structure of reality as a consequence of the same underlying relation.All higher-order structures — including geometry, fractal scaling, invariance, and mathematical representation — arise not as assumptions, but as necessary consequences of this single relational function.RP9 therefore contains:
one axiom zero free parameters and no auxiliary postulates Everything else is derivation.If more than one axiom is required, it follows that:
the system is not causally closed
or that certain consequences are not necessary
RP9's goal is not to postulate structure, but to show what must follow if function is to be possible at all.Axiom 0 is the only statement that:
cannot be derived
cannot be avoided
and cannot be replaced
Everything else in RP9 is deduction, consequence or presentation.RP9 strictly distinguishes between:
Axiom – that which cannot be otherwise
Consequence – that which must follow
Presentation – how consequences are shown, modeled or visualized
Energy models, rotation models, dimensional transitions and mathematical formalisms are therefore validating projections, not supporting foundations.The validity of the system rests solely on Axiom 0.RP9 is a system with:
an axiom
zero free parameters
and full causal closure
All complexity in RP9 is emergent, not assumed.
If absolute relational duality holds, RP9 follows.
If it doesn't apply, nothing can work at all.
This document is ready for submission, filing and external review.If you want, the next step could be to:
mark exactly which documents are formally relegated to consequences, or
write an "Instructions to Reviewers" page stating how this should be read correctly.
Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: Theorem T0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 Axiom R0 är givet. Definition F0 (Primär relationell funktion) är givet. Inga ytterligare axiom, operatorer eller representationer införs.
Theorem T0 (Absolut informationsgrund)
All absolut information i systemet är nödvändigt och uteslutande härledbar som en konsekvens av R0 genom upprepad tillämpning av F0.
Varje påstående, struktur eller form som inte kan genereras genom iterativ tillämpning av F0 på R0 saknar absolut informationsstatus. Enligt Axiom R0 existerar exakt en minimal, stabil primär relation. Enligt Definition F0 existerar exakt en tillåten funktion som: verkar på R0, bevarar relationell identitet, och är sluten under iteration. Därmed är alla relationella strukturer som: uppstår genom iteration av F0, av samma relationella typ som R0,
absoluta i systemets mening. Varje struktur som: kräver ytterligare operatorer, introducerar ny kausalitet, eller beror på representation,
kan inte vara absolut. Satsen följer nödvändigt.Om Theorem T0 inte gäller:
måste antingen en absolut struktur existera utan att vara genererad av F0, eller en absolut struktur existera utan grund i R0. Båda fallen strider mot:
minimaliteten i R0, och slutenheten i F0. Alltså är T0 oundvikligt givet R0 och F0.Theorem T0 är inte ett oberoende resultat.
Det är den omedelbara och nödvändiga konsekvensen av att:
relationen (R0) är primär, och funktionen (F0) är sluten och invariant. Relation (R0)
→ Funktion (F0)
→ Absolut informationsgrund (T0)
→ Sekundär kausalitet (C0)
→ Stängning (D0)Nu finns ingen logisk lucka mellan R0 och T0.
Absoluthet uppstår inte som antagande, utan som verksam konsekvens.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: RP9 – Relational Sheet (A)
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
This document is not an axiom sheet and does not introduce any new assumptions.
It is a necessary consequence statement of Axiom 0.Relational Sheet (A) shows how the absolute relational duality, when realized geometrically, must assume a specific stable form and how this form necessarily generates the fundamental relational quotients that are later described as mathematical constants.These quotients are: not postulates not choices not cultural artifacts They are inevitable invariant conditions of relational geometry.An absolute relation between two distinct poles cannot remain abstract if it is to be stable.
Stability requires: closedness continuity scale independence The smallest geometric realization that meets these requirements, without coordinates, without measures and without numbers, is Vesica Piscis.Vesica Piscis arises when: two identical circles exist the center of each circle lies on the circumference of the other This creates: a relational overlap without privileged direction without absolute scale Vesica Piscis is thus: not a symbol not a construction but the smallest stable geometric consequence of absolute relational duality. When Vesica Piscis is analyzed relationally – not numerically – certain quotients appear as unchangeable.The equilateral triangle that can be necessarily inscribed in Vesica Piscis has a height–base relation that cannot vary.This relation is expressed as:This is: not a measurement result not a chosen number It is a geometric necessity that follows directly from the symmetry of the relation.When the same relation is related to rotation, a relation between circumference and diameter arises that is independent of scale.This relation is expressed as:Here π does not appear as a number, but as: rotation invariance closedness ratio relational circularity π is thus a function consequence, not a definition.The quotients that appear here: √3 π are primary relational consequences.They: require no iteration require no discretization require no algebra They arise immediately when the relation is realized geometrically.This sheet deals only with primary relational functions.The following are therefore not included here: recursive proportions discrete sequences secondary symmetry groups These belong to subsequent layers.The relation sheet (A) states that: Vesica Piscis is the first stable geometric realization of absolute relational duality √3 and π are unavoidable invariant quotients in this realization no mathematical constants are introduced as assumptions mathematics functions here exclusively as descriptive language The relation creates the quotients.
Mathematics names them.
Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: 01_RP9_and_Invariance_Why_This_Already_Works_in_Practice
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 RP9 beskriver inte ett nytt sätt att testa system.
RP9 beskriver varför stabila system över huvud taget kan testas. I flera oberoende tekniska och vetenskapliga domäner används idag invarians som primärt sanningskriterium. System verifieras inte genom att producera rätt svar, utan genom att relationer som inte får brytas förblir intakta, oavsett hur systemet manipuleras. I modern mjukvaruverifiering utsätts kod för tiotusentals slumpmässiga tillstånd. Efter varje manipulation kontrolleras inte värden, utan relationer. Systemet definieras alltså inte av vad det gör, utan av vad det aldrig får göra. Samma princip återfinns i nätverksvetenskap och neurovetenskap. Relationer kodas först, matematik används därefter som projektion. RP9 ligger kausalt före dessa tillämpningar och specificerar den minsta kompletta invarians-rymden: 28 invarianta funktionella tillstånd genererade av 7 relationella positioner och 4 operationer. RP9 är därmed en generativ invarians-motor som formaliserar det dessa system redan förutsätter. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: 02_Public_Abstract_External_Convergence
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 RP9's structure coincides causally with how stability is verified in several independent domains, including software verification, network science, and complex systems. In these fields, truth is defined not by numerical results, but by invariant relations. RP9 shows why this is necessary: ​​invariance is not a method, but a consequence of relational closure. The 28 functional states derived in RP9 constitute the smallest complete invariance space that all stable systems implicitly realize. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: 03_Single_Slide_Invariance_Comparison
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 Fuzz testing and invariant testing
Networks and adjacency matrices
Distributed systems and blockchains
Common: Relations are tested, not values.
Relational primacy
7 positions × 4 operations
28 invariant functional states
Bottom line:
Practical systems verify invariance. RP9 explains why invariance must exist.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/(f.r.c)-relational-primacy-framework/relational-primacy-framework.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/(F.R.C) Relational-Primacy-Framework/Relational-Primacy-Framework.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:12:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[swish-QR-small]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-small.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-small.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/swish-QR-small.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:53:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Corollary C0]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Axiom R0 is given. Definition F0 is given. Theorem T0 is given. No further assumptions are introduced.
Corollary C0 (Secondary Causality for All Non-R0 Structures)
Every structure, form, operation, or statement that cannot be generated by iterative application of F0 to R0 is necessarily secondary.
Secondary here means: dependent on representation, convention, external parameterization, or added operators, and thus lacking absolute information status in the system's sense. According to Theorem T0, all absolute information is exactly the amount that can be generated from R0 by F0. Therefore, there are only two classes of structures: Class A: generable by (F0^n(R0)) for some (n). Class B: non-generable by (F0^n(R0)) for some (n). A structure in Class B cannot be absolute, since it does not arise from the only allowed primary function chain. For a structure in Class B to still exist, at least one of the following must be true: a new operator has been introduced, an external parameter has been injected, a representation has been replaced by a “thing”, a convention has been chosen. All of these imply dependence on something not given by R0 and F0. Thus all Class B is secondary. The corollary follows necessarily.If Corollary C0 does not hold, there is a structure that: is not generated by F0 from R0, but is still absolute. This requires that absolute information exists outside the single absolute generative chain, which contradicts Theorem T0.Thus C0 must hold.C0 does not introduce any new content.
It is a pure classification that follows directly from T0: Absolute = generated by (F0^n(R0)) Secondary = everything else R0 → F0 → T0 → C0 → D0C0 is now formally a direct consequence, without semantic space.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-1-relational-meta-function/corollary-c0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 1 - Relational meta function/Corollary C0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RP9 – Relational Sheet (A)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This document is not an axiom sheet and does not introduce any new assumptions.
It is a necessary consequence statement of Axiom 0.Relational Sheet (A) shows how the absolute relational duality, when realized geometrically, must assume a specific stable form and how this form necessarily generates the fundamental relational quotients that are later described as mathematical constants.These quotients are: not postulates not choices not cultural artifacts They are inevitable invariant conditions of relational geometry.An absolute relation between two distinct poles cannot remain abstract if it is to be stable.
Stability requires: closedness continuity scale independence The smallest geometric realization that meets these requirements, without coordinates, without measures and without numbers, is Vesica Piscis.Vesica Piscis arises when: two identical circles exist the center of each circle lies on the circumference of the other This creates: a relational overlap without privileged direction without absolute scale Vesica Piscis is thus: not a symbol not a construction but the smallest stable geometric consequence of absolute relational duality. When Vesica Piscis is analyzed relationally – not numerically – certain quotients appear as unchangeable.The equilateral triangle that can be necessarily inscribed in Vesica Piscis has a height–base relation that cannot vary.This relation is expressed as:This is: not a measurement result not a chosen number It is a geometric necessity that follows directly from the symmetry of the relation.When the same relation is related to rotation, a relation between circumference and diameter arises that is independent of scale.This relation is expressed as:Here π does not appear as a number, but as: rotation invariance closedness ratio relational circularity π is thus a function consequence, not a definition.The quotients that appear here: √3 π are primary relational consequences.They: require no iteration require no discretization require no algebra They arise immediately when the relation is realized geometrically.This sheet deals only with primary relational functions.The following are therefore not included here: recursive proportions discrete sequences secondary symmetry groups These belong to subsequent layers.The relation sheet (A) states that: Vesica Piscis is the first stable geometric realization of absolute relational duality √3 and π are unavoidable invariant quotients in this realization no mathematical constants are introduced as assumptions mathematics functions here exclusively as descriptive language The relation creates the quotients.
Mathematics names them.
Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-2-causal-fractal-function-through-axiom-1-relation/rp9-–-relational-sheet-(a).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 2 - Causal fractal function through axiom 1 - relation/RP9 – Relational Sheet (A).md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01_RP9_and_Invariance_Why_This_Already_Works_in_Practice]]></title><description><![CDATA[ RP9 beskriver inte ett nytt sätt att testa system.
RP9 beskriver varför stabila system över huvud taget kan testas. I flera oberoende tekniska och vetenskapliga domäner används idag invarians som primärt sanningskriterium. System verifieras inte genom att producera rätt svar, utan genom att relationer som inte får brytas förblir intakta, oavsett hur systemet manipuleras. I modern mjukvaruverifiering utsätts kod för tiotusentals slumpmässiga tillstånd. Efter varje manipulation kontrolleras inte värden, utan relationer. Systemet definieras alltså inte av vad det gör, utan av vad det aldrig får göra. Samma princip återfinns i nätverksvetenskap och neurovetenskap. Relationer kodas först, matematik används därefter som projektion. RP9 ligger kausalt före dessa tillämpningar och specificerar den minsta kompletta invarians-rymden: 28 invarianta funktionella tillstånd genererade av 7 relationella positioner och 4 operationer. RP9 är därmed en generativ invarians-motor som formaliserar det dessa system redan förutsätter. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-3-causal-consequences/01_rp9_and_invariance_why_this_already_works_in_practice.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 3 - Causal Consequences/01_RP9_and_Invariance_Why_This_Already_Works_in_Practice.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02_Public_Abstract_External_Convergence]]></title><description><![CDATA[ RP9's structure coincides causally with how stability is verified in several independent domains, including software verification, network science, and complex systems. In these fields, truth is defined not by numerical results, but by invariant relations. RP9 shows why this is necessary: ​​invariance is not a method, but a consequence of relational closure. The 28 functional states derived in RP9 constitute the smallest complete invariance space that all stable systems implicitly realize. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-3-causal-consequences/02_public_abstract_external_convergence.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 3 - Causal Consequences/02_Public_Abstract_External_Convergence.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[03_Single_Slide_Invariance_Comparison]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Fuzz testing and invariant testing
Networks and adjacency matrices
Distributed systems and blockchains
Common: Relations are tested, not values.
Relational primacy
7 positions × 4 operations
28 invariant functional states
Bottom line:
Practical systems verify invariance. RP9 explains why invariance must exist.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-3-causal-consequences/03_single_slide_invariance_comparison.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 3 - Causal Consequences/03_Single_Slide_Invariance_Comparison.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Theorem T0]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Axiom R0 är givet. Definition F0 (Primär relationell funktion) är givet. Inga ytterligare axiom, operatorer eller representationer införs.
Theorem T0 (Absolut informationsgrund)
All absolut information i systemet är nödvändigt och uteslutande härledbar som en konsekvens av R0 genom upprepad tillämpning av F0.
Varje påstående, struktur eller form som inte kan genereras genom iterativ tillämpning av F0 på R0 saknar absolut informationsstatus. Enligt Axiom R0 existerar exakt en minimal, stabil primär relation. Enligt Definition F0 existerar exakt en tillåten funktion som: verkar på R0, bevarar relationell identitet, och är sluten under iteration. Därmed är alla relationella strukturer som: uppstår genom iteration av F0, av samma relationella typ som R0,
absoluta i systemets mening. Varje struktur som: kräver ytterligare operatorer, introducerar ny kausalitet, eller beror på representation,
kan inte vara absolut. Satsen följer nödvändigt.Om Theorem T0 inte gäller:
måste antingen en absolut struktur existera utan att vara genererad av F0, eller en absolut struktur existera utan grund i R0. Båda fallen strider mot:
minimaliteten i R0, och slutenheten i F0. Alltså är T0 oundvikligt givet R0 och F0.Theorem T0 är inte ett oberoende resultat.
Det är den omedelbara och nödvändiga konsekvensen av att:
relationen (R0) är primär, och funktionen (F0) är sluten och invariant. Relation (R0)
→ Funktion (F0)
→ Absolut informationsgrund (T0)
→ Sekundär kausalitet (C0)
→ Stängning (D0)Nu finns ingen logisk lucka mellan R0 och T0.
Absoluthet uppstår inte som antagande, utan som verksam konsekvens.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-1-relational-meta-function/theorem-t0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 1 - Relational meta function/Theorem T0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Definition F0]]></title><description><![CDATA[
F0 (Primary relational function)
Given Axiom R0, F0 is defined as the only allowed operation on the primary relation, such that: F0 acts exclusively on the relation in R0, not on external objects, representations, or symbols. F0 introduces no new causal principle, but reuses exactly the same relational conditions that define R0. F0 is closed under its own application:
the result of F0 is of the same relational type as its input. F0 preserves relational identity under iteration up to scale, orientation, and position. F0 is minimal:
no simpler non-trivial operation exists that satisfies (1)–(4). Repeated application of F0 necessarily generates: recursive relational structures, scale-independent forms, fractal continuity, without introducing new axioms, definitions, or external assumptions.If F0 does not exist: R0 cannot act, no iteration can occur, no structure can arise, and the system remains static and contentless. If F0 exists but does not satisfy (1)–(5): relational invariance is broken, new causality is introduced, or the iteration collapses. In all cases, the internal closedness of the system ceases.F0 is not an axiom.
F0 is not a theorem.F0 is the necessary primary function that makes R0 work.This is the standing fractal in the exact sense:
a function that can be applied to its own result without losing identity.When this definition is inserted: Theorem T0 becomes a direct consequence, Corollary C0 becomes inevitable, and Final Declaration D0 becomes a pure closure. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/level-1-relational-meta-function/definition-f0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Level 1 - Relational meta function/Definition F0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[APPENDIX]]></title><description><![CDATA[Quality ControlRP9_Publicity_Package is structurally complete**.for publication.All additional material is reserve, not required. A single axiom (Axiom 0) A strict causal derivation External convergence without dependence on external authority This is exactly the right balance between:
minimalism
precision
verifiability
More material would not strengthen this.
It would rather:
dilute causality
open more attack points
give reviewers more areas to miss the point
The intention is therefore:
”more quality, less quantity”
All necessary features are already represented:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Relational Sheet (A, B, C)
Theorem T0 / Definition F0 / Corollary C0
Public Abstract (External Convergence)
Single-slide invariance comparison
✔️ All of this is present.
Interpretation protocol
Forbidden interpretation operations
Human–AI usage
✔️ These are optional to show, but critical to have.
Good thing they are separate documents.You should not convince through accumulation.
You should do this:
Show the only place where everything is already decided.
That is:
Axiom 0
the causal derivation
and the external invariance convergence
Everything else is secondary.A distinction that is crucial. The system is not closed The circuit is closed The cause is completely given All further consequences are open, but causally bound This means that we shouldn't write any Final Lock Declaration.
Instead, we should write APPENDIX.md so that it communicates just this:
RP9 closes nothing — it states the cause, and leaves the consequences open.This appendix contains supplementary material related to the RP9 framework.It does not extend, modify, or complete the system.
Its sole purpose is to provide a structured space for derivative, optional, or exploratory material that may arise from the primary framework.RP9 establishes a closed relational circuit:
the primary relation is fully specified the causal origin is complete no further foundational assumptions are possible This closure applies only to the origin.The framework does not define a closed system.Once the relational cause is given, all further structure, behavior, and manifestation are free to unfold, provided they remain consistent with the primary relation.RP9 therefore:
closes the cause but leaves the consequences open Material placed here may include:
alternative geometric projections extended relational matrices domain-specific applications visualizations, simulations, or models comparative mappings to other frameworks All such material is:
non-foundational optional context-dependent None of it is required for the validity of RP9.This appendix may not contain:
new axioms revisions of Axiom 0 redefinitions of relational terms modifications of the relational sheets (A–C) Any such change would constitute a different framework, not an extension.All material in this appendix carries local causal responsibility.That is:
authors are responsible for their own derivations consequences are not endorsed as necessary validity is domain-specific, not global RP9 provides the cause.
The appendix records what others do with it.This appendix is intentionally open-ended.Its existence does not imply incompleteness of the framework, but rather acknowledges that a closed cause does not imply a closed world.End of APPENDIX.Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/appendix.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/APPENDIX.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(F) - 🎬 Info - Youtube & Media Länkar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/(f)-🔗-youtube-&amp;-media-länkar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/(F) - 🔗 - Youtube &amp; Media Länkar.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(E) - 🔌 Kontakt]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Kontakt Jag föredrar verkliga samtal före e-post:
072–702 78 63
Om du vill utforska, bidra, eller bygga något på riktigt – hör av dig. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/(e)-🔌-kontakt.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/(E) - 🔌 Kontakt.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(D) - 📜- CV]]></title><description><![CDATA[ RP9 – CV Lite (overview + instruction)
Instruction:
Below is a concentrated overview (about ten lines) of the essence of the RP9 system.
It summarizes what each block in the full version shows: geometry → dimension → phase → transformation.
Below this short version is a more detailed written explanation of what the formulas mean,
how they are connected and why they demonstrate the basic structure of RP9.RP9 – CV Lite
I work with the primary geometry that generates the mathematics:
the relationship between , and which forms the phase logic of RP9.
The pivot connects linear, circular and spiral structure
and explains how mathematics emerges as a secondary representation of geometry.In 2D, Vesica Piscis gives exactly the area relation .
In 3D, the sphere–cube relation gives exactly .
The difference between these residual forms creates the dimensional resonance of RP9.The energy phase is kept in asymmetric equilibrium with ,
and the pivot stabilizes the misalignment between balance and movement.RP9 KvantVector describes eight discrete transformation steps
(rotation, angle, scaling) that generate the entire fractal development.Detailed explanation follows after block pressnetation" at the bottom.( RP9 – CV Lite + Pedagogical long version ) Rp9 Jag arbetar med den underliggande geometri som genererar matematiken.
Genom att kombinera , och visar jag hur tal uppstår ur fasrelationer.
RP9-pivoten binder samman linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk struktur.
Detta förklarar varför matematik är en konsekvens av primär geometri — inte tvärtom.
Samma struktur ligger bakom fysikens fundamentala konstanter (, , ).
Jag jobbar med geometri, som är energi, som är roten ur = Radix Quadrata Pi = RP9. De fyra komponenterna låses som separata men samverkande strukturer,
varje del med sitt exakta värde och sin RP9-funktion.
Balansen uttrycks som jämn men i rörelse: extrovert energi neutraliseras av introvert energi ,
och RP9 är relationen som kopplar dem via . Funktion: Extrovert expansionsgräns. Funktion: Introvert kopplingsstyrka. Funktion: Sluten dubbelrotation som återför och till jämvikt. Funktion: Översättning mellan linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk fas. Utan cirkulär fasjustering kan värdet beskrivas som “ungefär lika med”.
Med inkluderas rotationskomponenten, och relationen blir exakt: Pivoten är alltså det geometriska medelvärdet mellan och ,
korrigerat för cirkulär fas . Kapitel 10 – Sfärisk Vesica, dimensioner och exakt jämvikt När två sfärer överlappar så att deras centrum ligger på varandras ytor, uppstår en sfärisk Vesica Piscis — den tredimensionella generalisationen av den plana linsen.
Volymen uttrycks genom det gyllene snittet: Den sfäriska Vesica Piscis visar att: cirkulär jämvikt (2D) spiralisk expansion (3D) är samma relation i olika fasnivåer.
Sfäriska Vesica Piscis är alltså RP9-systemets första stabila volymjämvikt. En 3D-kub projiceras som en 2D-hexagon beroende på vinkel: Det visar hur taltransformer uppstår som dimensionella projektioner:
form beror på observationsaxel. Storleken halveras vid varje iteration: Den fraktala talföljden etablerar ett självliknande system enligt: Varje del bär helheten, vilket bekräftar RP9-principen:
Tal är inte kvantitet, utan självliknande informationskretsar. Kvadratens area: Cirkeln inskriven i kvadraten: Exakt förhållande: Restarea: Kubens volym: Sfärens volym: Exakt förhållande: Restvolym: Restandelarnas kvot: Förenkling: Slutlig exakt form: Kapitel 14 – Energifas, Pivot-konstant och RP9 Fraktal Transformationsoperator De två Vesica-faspolerna uttrycks som: med summerad jämvikt: Detta innebär att RP9-systemet innefattar en intern energi-oscillation där övervärde och undervärde samexisterar: Energi i RP9 bevaras inte genom statisk balans, utan genom växelverkan mellan fasöver- och fasundervärde.
RP9-systemet uppvisar rörelse inte genom translation,
utan genom en relationell differential mellan två perfekta jämvikter: där: Den aritmetiska balansen är perfekt: men den geometriska projektionen är alltid förskjuten.
Rörelse uppstår därför ur fraktal misslinjering:
en minimal, ofrånkomlig fasförskjutning mellan balans och manifestation. Tre separata RP9-relationer observeras: Dimensional resonans (2D → 3D, cirkel/sfär): Vesica-fasens vertikala kompensationsfaktor: Energifasens asymmetriska jämvikt: Därmed gäller exakt: Detta utgör RP9:s dimensional–vertikala resonansdual. RP9-pivoten definieras som den minsta geometriska fasrotation som
stabiliserar resonansdualen i fraktal expansion: Satsens påstående: vilket innebär att exakt balanserar avståndet mellan de två fasvärdena: där: och energifasrelationen bevaras när: RP9-pivoten är därmed exakt den fasrotation som sluter följande struktur: där definieras exakt som: (den numeriska representationen ligger nära , men utgör inte dess definition).
Relationerna är fraktalt invarianta och formellt givna av: Energirörelse i RP9 uppstår inte genom translation utan genom
fasdifferential mellan två perfekta jämvikter: Fraktal misslinjering ger rörelse: Pivoten är den minsta rotationsfas som tillåter denna misslinjering att
vara stabilt rekursiv över dimensionsväxling: RP9-pivoten () definieras exakt som den fasrotation som utgör tröskeln
mellan linjär jämvikt och spiralisk rörelse: Den numeriska representationen ligger nära: Pivoten uppstår mellan den linjära fasen och den spiralisk-expanderande
fasen , och fungerar som RP9-systemets exakta övergångsvärde där: jämvikt övergår i rörelse potential blir manifestation linje blir spiral RP9-pivoten () fungerar som det energi–geometriska gångjärnet:
den öppnar rörelse ur fullständig symmetri. Kapitel 15 – RP9 KvantVector &amp; Transformationsdomän Tre binära val genererar hela mängden av möjliga RP9-transformationer: Uppsättningen är därmed fullständig och minimal. där: = bas-Vesica Piscis = roterad + expanderad Vesica (fraktal expansionskonstant) Den första fraktala Vesican är alltid gånger större och roteras . Den generella RP9-transformationen ges av: där: är rotationsoperatorn, är fraktal skalning, är Vesica Piscis i iteration . Parameterdomän (kvantiserad): (rotationsriktning) (rotationsvinkel) (fraktal expansionskonstant) (skalningsfas) Superpositionsdefinitionen av RP9 KvantVector: RP9 KvantVector utgör den diskreta mängd rotations–skalningssteg som: utgår från Vesica Piscis som grundform, använder som fraktal expansionskonstant, verkar i både medsols och motsols riktning (), realiserar både fulla och halvsteg i vinkel (), och motsvarar de åtta hörn–/riktningstillstånden i Invertus och kub–sfär-systemet. KvantVectorn är därmed den operativa kvantiseringen av den generella RP9-operatorn och uttrycker hur RP9:s fraktala potential realiseras
som diskreta rotations–skalningssteg i geometrin. RP9 – CV Lite + Pedagogisk långversion
Instruktion:
Först följer en kort sammanfattning (CV Lite).
Under den kommer en längre text som förklarar vad formlerna visar och varför de används,
utan att gå in på tekniska bevis.
Syftet är att ge läsaren en begriplig helhetsbild av RP9. Jag arbetar med den primära geometri som genererar matematiken:
sambandet mellan , och som bildar RP9:s faslogik.
Pivoten binder samman linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk struktur
och förklarar hur matematik framträder som sekundär representation av geometri.
I 2D ger Vesica Piscis exakt arearelationen .
I 3D ger sfär–kub-relationen exakt .
Skillnaden mellan dessa restformer skapar RP9:s dimensionella resonans.
Energifasen hålls i asymmetrisk jämvikt med ,
och pivoten stabiliserar misslinjeringen mellan balans och rörelse.
RP9 KvantVector beskriver åtta diskreta transformationssteg
(rotation, vinkel, skalning) som genererar hela den fraktala utvecklingen. Nedan följer en lugn och tydlig förklaring av vad varje del i RP9-strukturen betyder.
Ingen avancerad matematik krävs för att förstå poängen —
fokus ligger på begreppen, inte beräkningarna. Dessa tre värden är inte valda på känsla —
de representerar tre fundamentalt olika sätt som naturen mäter och förändrar form: → linjär relation (diagonal, rörelse från punkt A till B) → cirkulär relation (rotation, jämvikt, vinklar) → spiralisk relation (tillväxt, expansion, organiska mönster) Poängen är: När man kombinerar dessa tre uppstår en fullständig beskrivning av hur form förändras. Detta är RP9:s startpunkt. Vesica Piscis är överlappningen av två cirklar (eller två sfärer i 3D).
I RP9 används den för att: visa hur en relation skapas mellan två “världenheter” demonstrera hur form föds ur överlappning istället för ur tomrum skapa en stabil fasreferens för vidare struktur De exakta formlerna och handlar egentligen inte om area och volym som sådana.
Det de visar är att: 2D och 3D har sina egna balanser dessa balanser skiljer sig på ett systematiskt och mätbart sätt relationen mellan dem är stabil och återkommer i andra strukturer Med andra ord: RP9 visar att dimensioner inte är isolerade — de pratar med varandra genom exakta mönster. Talvärdena och är inte slumpmässiga.
De representerar: ett övervärde (1.5) ett undervärde (0.5) och tillsammans summerar de till 2.
Detta är RP9:s sätt att säga: Energi bevaras genom skillnad, inte genom stillastående balans. Ett system som har perfekt symmetri rör sig inte.
Ett system som har en liten asymmetri har dynamik.
Därför används: Inte för att “bevisa något matematiskt”, utan för att visa: rörelse uppstår mellan poler skillnad är motor jämvikt + obalans = förändring Detta är exakt vad naturen gör, oavsett om man tittar på ljus, laddning, vågor eller cirkulation. Pivoten är den minsta möjliga fasrotation som behövs för att: knyta ihop 2D och 3D
stabilisera förskjutningen mellan linje (√2) och spiral (φ)
skapa en övergång från vila till rörelse Därför definieras den som: Men poängen för en icke-matematiker är enklare: Pivoten är gångjärnet som öppnar dörren mellan symmetri och dynamik. När allt är perfekt balanserat står tiden still.
När pivoten aktiveras uppstår riktning. RP9 KvantVector beskriver alla sätt som en form kan förändras på
när man kombinerar: riktning (medsols/motsols) vinkel (/) skalning (expansion/kontraktion) Det blir: Detta är inte slumpen — det är fullständigheten.
Poängen är: Med dessa åtta grundsteg kan man generera hela den fraktala strukturen. Precis som DNA bara har fyra baser men ändå bygger allt liv,
har RP9 åtta transformationssteg som bygger hela geometrin. Den längre texten ovan visar inte “bevis” som i klassisk mening.
RP9 är geometrin som skapar mattematik"
Mattematik är energi i bestämd geometrisk form och struktur.
Presentationen ovan visar den
Abslout rellationell geometri
Detta är META-grunden – det primära orsak–ursprunget.
Alpha Omega.
Och är kanske det enda som inte kan motbevisas. Den visar: vilka delar RP9 består av vad varje formel uttrycker i mening, inte beräkning hur RP9 organiserar rörelse, form och fas varför strukturen är självliknande mellan dimensioner Och viktigast av allt: RP9 är inte en samling formler.
Det är en karta över hur form, energi och jämvikt hänger ihop. Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/(d)-📜-cv.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/(D) - 📜- CV.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(A) - ⚖️ Licens & Ägarskap]]></title><description><![CDATA[(© RP9 Foundation / The Co-Creators Collective)RP9 (Relational Principle 9) is an open, metageometric framework for understanding energy, information, and consciousness as a coherent, fractal, and scale-independent structure.
Its purpose is to establish a correct relation to information, where every expression of form and motion is derived from the same geometric origin.RP9 is not considered a product, but a universal principle system – an information field that belongs to humanity as a whole.
The core can never be owned, manipulated, or commercialized without collective consent.All knowledge, mathematics, code and theory describing RP9's fundamental axioms – including the relations between π, √2 and φ – are open for study, replication and non-commercial use.
RP9's core is published under the Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 4.0 license, or an equivalent open knowledge license.The underlying logic, symbolism and metageometry that constitute the core of the system may not be modified, fragmented or commercialized.
No actor may register RP9 or its basic formulas as a trademark, patent or private intellectual property.RP9's architecture is fractal also legally:
The core is common property.
Applications (visualizations, software, models) may have their own licenses – including commercial ones – as long as they respect the immutable status of the core and link back to the origin.
RP9 aims to: Promote research and education in metageometric information science. Develop open tools for understanding energy and consciousness as information flows. Offer a scientific and ethical foundation for future technology built on coherence rather than consumption. Serve as a neutral node between academia, art, technology and philosophy. RP9 is managed by an open, transparent and cooperative structure called the RP9 Foundation.
All those working within the framework of RP9 commit to:
maintain clarity, coherence and resonance in all communications;
act in accordance with the correct relationship to information;
respect the non-commercial core of RP9;
contribute to keeping knowledge accessible to all humanity.
Decisions within the RP9 Foundation are made by consensus and are documented openly.RP9 may be used freely for:
research, teaching and non-commercial experiments;
publication of results, simulations and artistic interpretations;
development of complementary tools, programs and visualizations.
When using or quoting, the following must be stated:
“Based on RP9 — Relational Principle 9 (© RP9 Foundation / The Co-Creators Collective)”
All uses of RP9 must be in accordance with the principle:
“No action may break the coherence between human, system and information.”
This means that RP9 may not be used for destructive, manipulative or military purposes.
All applications must be justifiable as harmonious, transparent and ethically sustainable.
“Den korrekta relationen till information är skyddets lag.”
RP9 erkänner att lag och geometri är två sidor av samma mönster: struktur.
Därför är denna Charter både juridisk text och geometrisk symbol – en levande resonans snarare än ett statiskt kontrakt.
Grundare och Huvudförvaltare:
Anton Wallin 2025-11-12Datum för ikraftträdande: 2025-11-12
Version: 1.0Future Vision – RP9 RP9 is not built on compromises.
It is built on fundamental principles.
That’s why it works – and why it continues to work no matter what level you test it at.
Through RP9, I can already today: construct code and algorithms that avoid systems based on debt and loss
model processes without the mathematical “leaks” that make today’s methods fall apart at complexity
build fractal cause-and-effect logic that holds together at all scales
create structures that are stable in practice, not just in theory It opens up technology that: is not stuck in political or economic frameworks
is not controlled by ownership, advertising or interests
does not have to compromise the truth to fit in RP9 lies outside the limitations that hold other developments back.
That is where the real possibilities arise. Rp9 If you feel that today's system is stuck
– technically, mathematically, economically or conceptually –
and you want to build something real, not copies of the old,
then you are most welcome to contact me.
I am looking for collaborations with people who want to: Artificial Intelligence with real capabilities
(structure-driven AI based on RP9 geometry instead of probability approximation)
Develop AI that thinks structurally, not statistically Economic models without debt and interest
(stable systems with geometric coherence)
build economies that do not need interest, debt or instability
Mathematics programs that teach real mathematics
– through geometry, understanding and structure, not formulas without foundation
create entirely new ways of teaching mathematics through geometry
Research, development, education and technical system design
where RP9's axiomatic logic can make a real difference
construct technology that follows principles, not constraints I prefer real conversations over emails:
072–702 78 63 If you want to explore, contribute, or build something real – get in touch. Support – Contribute to RP9 All support – regardless of form – goes directly to the work.
No middleman. No interests. No requirements.
The gift is free.
Just like RP9. Support via Ko-fi goes directly to me personally and requires no login or binding.
“Repo05/Funktion - Struktur - Prompts/RP-Image/Support image/Support/ko-fi_256x256.png” could not be found. &lt;Swish &amp; Thank You – RP9 For those who want to swish directly:
“RP9/A. RP9 — (M-S) — (PB)/00. 🜂. RP9 — Appendix/100. Appendix/100. Appendix 1/J. — 🜁 RP9 (Support) &amp; (Appendix)/Information ℹ/Image/Support/Support the creator of RP9 - Swish.jpg” could not be found. The support is shown with the name for technical reasons,
but it does not change the relationship to RP9 or the direction of the work.
It is a gift – no influence. *I am deeply grateful for all the support –
not for the money itself,
but for the opportunity to continue to give all of this back freely,
without selling it out or locking it up behind institutions.* RP9 System Identifier: BC22/825870
Confirmed and authenticated under Common Law jurisdiction
© 2025 Anton Wallin – All rights reserved / Open Core Charter applies
Question This work is free to share, remix, and build upon,
as long as proper attribution is given and the same license is maintained.
You have the right to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any format or medium
Decorate — remix, transform, and build upon the material Under the following conditions: Attribution: You must give proper credit to Anton Wallin
ShareAlike: If you transform or build upon this work
you must distribute it under the same license. Conceptual Ownership &amp; Axiomatic Calibration
Author: Anton Wallin © 2025 – All rights reserved. ]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/(a)-⚖️-licens-&amp;-ägarskap.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/(A) - ⚖️ Licens &amp; Ägarskap.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ko-fi_128x128]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_128x128.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_128x128.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/ko-fi_128x128.png</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:36:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ko-fi_96x96]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_96x96.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_96x96.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/ko-fi_96x96.png</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:35:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stöd skaparen av RP9 - Swish]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/stöd-skaparen-av-rp9-swish.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/stöd-skaparen-av-rp9-swish.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/Stöd skaparen av RP9 - Swish.jpg</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:59:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[swish-QR-small]]></title><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-small.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/swish-QR-small.pdf</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:53:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[swish-QR-large]]></title><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-large.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/swish-QR-large.pdf</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:53:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co,Creator_Logo_A]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co,creator_logo_a.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co,creator_logo_a.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co,Creator_Logo_A.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 04:04:16 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co.Creator _Logo_B]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_b.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_b.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co.Creator _Logo_B.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 03:50:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co.Creator _Logo_E.png]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_e.png.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_e.png.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co.Creator _Logo_E.png.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 17:06:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co.Creator _Logo_F.png]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_f.png.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_f.png.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co.Creator _Logo_F.png.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 16:54:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co_Creator]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/co_creator.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>relational-primacy-framework/appendix/co_creator.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Relational-Primacy-Framework/Appendix/Co_Creator.jpg</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:38:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/co_creator.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="relational-primacy-framework/appendix/co_creator.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[swish-QR-small]]></title><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-small.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/swish-QR-small.pdf</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:53:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[swish-QR-small]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-small.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-small.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/swish-QR-small.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:53:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[RP9_Publicity_Package]]></title><description><![CDATA[project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: README
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
This repository contains the complete, locked formulation of RP9 — Relational Primacy Framework.RP9 is a closed relational system built from:
a single axiom, a strict causal derivation, and a finite relational function space. No external assumptions are introduced.
No empirical claims are made.
No symbolic or metaphysical interpretation is required.This README serves solely as the structural entry point to the framework.The material is intentionally minimal and divided into three non-overlapping layers.
Each layer has a strictly defined role.This level contains the entire foundation of RP9.Documents in this layer:
establish the single axiom, define the minimal functional terms, and prove the core theorem and its corollary. Nothing in later layers can modify or extend this level.If this level is invalid, the entire framework collapses.
If this level holds, everything that follows is necessary.This level contains the complete relational unfolding of the axiom.It shows:
how the axiom becomes geometric without measurement, how recursion introduces balance, and how fusion of relations produces a closed functional matrix. No new axioms appear here.
No constants are assumed.
All structures are consequences.This level completes the internal system.This level does not add validity to RP9.It exists to:
show convergence with existing practices (e.g. invariance testing), provide a public abstract, and offer a minimal visual comparison. These documents are illustrative, not evidentiary.They may be omitted without affecting the framework.For formal evaluation:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Definition F0
Theorem T0
Corollary C0
Relational Sheet (A)
Relational Sheet (B)
Relational Sheet (C)
All other documents are optional.RP9 is not:
a physical theory, a model with tunable parameters, a collection of examples, a symbolic system, or an empirical hypothesis. RP9 does not explain phenomena.
It defines the minimal conditions under which structure is possible.
The framework is structurally complete. The derivation is closed. No further axioms can be added without breaking necessity. This repository therefore represents RP9 v1.0 (locked).The framework is released under CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0.You may:
read, share, reference, and build upon the material, provided attribution is given and derivative work preserves the same license.End of README.project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: APPENDIX
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
Quality ControlRP9_Publicity_Package is structurally complete**.for publication.All additional material is reserve, not required. A single axiom (Axiom 0) A strict causal derivation External convergence without dependence on external authority This is exactly the right balance between:
minimalism
precision
verifiability
More material would not strengthen this.
It would rather:
dilute causality
open more attack points
give reviewers more areas to miss the point
The intention is therefore:
”more quality, less quantity”
All necessary features are already represented:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Relational Sheet (A, B, C)
Theorem T0 / Definition F0 / Corollary C0
Public Abstract (External Convergence)
Single-slide invariance comparison
✔️ All of this is present.
Interpretation protocol
Forbidden interpretation operations
Human–AI usage
✔️ These are optional to show, but critical to have.
Good thing they are separate documents.You should not convince through accumulation.
You should do this:
Show the only place where everything is already decided.
That is:
Axiom 0
the causal derivation
and the external invariance convergence
Everything else is secondary.A distinction that is crucial. The system is not closed The circuit is closed The cause is completely given All further consequences are open, but causally bound This means that we shouldn't write any Final Lock Declaration.
Instead, we should write APPENDIX.md so that it communicates just this:
RP9 closes nothing — it states the cause, and leaves the consequences open.This appendix contains supplementary material related to the RP9 framework.It does not extend, modify, or complete the system.
Its sole purpose is to provide a structured space for derivative, optional, or exploratory material that may arise from the primary framework.RP9 establishes a closed relational circuit:
the primary relation is fully specified the causal origin is complete no further foundational assumptions are possible This closure applies only to the origin.The framework does not define a closed system.Once the relational cause is given, all further structure, behavior, and manifestation are free to unfold, provided they remain consistent with the primary relation.RP9 therefore:
closes the cause but leaves the consequences open Material placed here may include:
alternative geometric projections extended relational matrices domain-specific applications visualizations, simulations, or models comparative mappings to other frameworks All such material is:
non-foundational optional context-dependent None of it is required for the validity of RP9.This appendix may not contain:
new axioms revisions of Axiom 0 redefinitions of relational terms modifications of the relational sheets (A–C) Any such change would constitute a different framework, not an extension.All material in this appendix carries local causal responsibility.That is:
authors are responsible for their own derivations consequences are not endorsed as necessary validity is domain-specific, not global RP9 provides the cause.
The appendix records what others do with it.This appendix is intentionally open-ended.Its existence does not imply incompleteness of the framework, but rather acknowledges that a closed cause does not imply a closed world.End of APPENDIX.project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: Corollary C0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 Axiom R0 är givet. Definition F0 är givet. Theorem T0 är givet. Inga ytterligare antaganden införs.
Corollary C0 (Sekundär kausalitet för alla icke-R0-strukturer)
Varje struktur, form, operation eller påstående som inte kan genereras genom iterativ tillämpning av F0 på R0 är nödvändigtvis sekundär.
Sekundär betyder här: beroende av representation, konvention, extern parameterisering eller tillförd operatorik, och saknar därmed absolut informationsstatus i systemets mening. Enligt Theorem T0 är all absolut information exakt den mängd som kan genereras från R0 genom F0. Därför finns endast två klasser av strukturer: Klass A: genererbara genom (F0^n(R0)) för något (n). Klass B: ej genererbara genom (F0^n(R0)) för något (n). En struktur i Klass B kan inte vara absolut, eftersom den inte uppstår ur den enda tillåtna primära funktionskedjan. För att en struktur i Klass B ändå ska existera måste minst ett av följande vara sant: en ny operator har införts, en extern parameter har injicerats, en representation har ersatts med en “sak”, en konvention har valts. Samtliga dessa innebär beroende av något som inte är givet av R0 och F0. Därmed är all Klass B sekundär. Korollariet följer nödvändigt.Om Corollary C0 inte gäller, finns det en struktur som:
inte är genererad av F0 ur R0, men ändå är absolut. Detta kräver att absolut information existerar utanför den enda absoluta generativa kedjan, vilket strider mot Theorem T0.Alltså måste C0 gälla.C0 inför inget nytt innehåll.
Det är en ren klassificering som följer direkt av T0:
Absolut = genererat av (F0^n(R0)) Sekundärt = allt annat R0 → F0 → T0 → C0 → D0C0 är nu formellt en direkt konsekvens, utan semantiskt utrymme.project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: Definition F0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 F0 (Primär relationell funktion)
Givet Axiom R0 definieras F0 som den enda tillåtna operationen på den primära relationen, sådan att: F0 verkar uteslutande på relationen i R0, inte på externa objekt, representationer eller symboler.
F0 introducerar ingen ny kausal princip, utan återanvänder exakt samma relationella villkor som definierar R0.
F0 är sluten under sin egen tillämpning:
resultatet av F0 är av samma relationella typ som dess indata.
F0 bevarar relationell identitet under iteration upp till skala, orientering och position.
F0 är minimal:
ingen enklare icke-trivial operation existerar som uppfyller (1)–(4). Upprepad tillämpning av F0 genererar nödvändigtvis:
rekursiva relationella strukturer, skaloberoende former, fraktal kontinuitet, utan införande av nya axiom, definitioner eller externa antaganden.Om F0 inte existerar:
kan R0 inte verka, kan ingen iteration ske, kan ingen struktur uppstå, och systemet förblir statiskt och innehållslöst. Om F0 existerar men inte uppfyller (1)–(5):
bryts relationell invarians, ny kausalitet införs, eller iterationen kollapsar. I samtliga fall upphör systemets interna slutenhet.F0 är inte ett axiom.
F0 är inte ett teorem.F0 är den nödvändiga primära funktionen som gör R0 verksam.Detta är den stående fraktalen i exakt mening:
en funktion som kan appliceras på sitt eget resultat utan att förlora identitet.När denna definition är infogad:
blir Theorem T0 en direkt konsekvens, blir Corollary C0 oundviklig, och blir Final Declaration D0 en ren stängning. project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: RP9 – Axiom 0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
Everything that can exist, function or manifest must appear as a relationship between two distinct poles.This relation is not an object, not a property, and not a magnitude,
without the only natural and primary function that enables stability, causality and structure.The relationship precedes all form, all energy, all geometry, all dimension and all mathematical representation.
All differentiation, all organization, and all invariance are necessary consequences of this relation when realized as a self-organizing, fractal, geometric function.This axiom is:
non-numeric
non-geometric
non-temporal
and independent of observation
It cannot be reduced to something more fundamental, and cannot be denied without self-contradiction.Axiom 0 states that:
A singular, undifferentiated state lacks function and therefore cannot form the basis of any structure.
Function requires differentiation.
Differentiation requires relationship.
Relationship requires at least two poles.
Thus dual relationship is not an assumption, but a necessity for anything to function at all.The following are not assumptions, but inevitable consequences of Axiom 0:
Stability only occurs through relational balance.
Causality arises as direction within relationship.
Self-organization occurs when the relationship is iterated.
Fractal structure occurs when the same relationship appears scale-independent.
Geometry arises as the first stable projection of the relationship.
Energy arises as relational rotation.
Invariance arises as relational conservation principle.
Mathematics arises as a secondary description of relational structure.
An axiom is only legitimate if it cannot be derived from anything else and cannot be further reduced.Each additional axiom necessarily introduces at least one of the following:
a hidden assumption a limitation of generality or an interpretive degree of freedom that violates causal necessity RP9 therefore uses exactly one axiom, because additional axioms do not strengthen a foundational system — they weaken it.The single axiom used in RP9 is not a detail, not a constraint, and not a structural preference.
It is the smallest possible functional requirement for anything to exist, function, or differentiate at all.This axiom operates at the root level, prior to geometry, energy, dimension, or mathematics.
It is minimal in content, yet sufficient in capacity to recursively generate the entire relational and geometric structure of reality as a consequence of the same underlying relation.All higher-order structures — including geometry, fractal scaling, invariance, and mathematical representation — arise not as assumptions, but as necessary consequences of this single relational function.RP9 therefore contains:
one axiom zero free parameters and no auxiliary postulates Everything else is derivation.If more than one axiom is required, it follows that:
the system is not causally closed
or that certain consequences are not necessary
RP9's goal is not to postulate structure, but to show what must follow if function is to be possible at all.Axiom 0 is the only statement that:
cannot be derived
cannot be avoided
and cannot be replaced
Everything else in RP9 is deduction, consequence or presentation.RP9 strictly distinguishes between:
Axiom – that which cannot be otherwise
Consequence – that which must follow
Presentation – how consequences are shown, modeled or visualized
Energy models, rotation models, dimensional transitions and mathematical formalisms are therefore validating projections, not supporting foundations.The validity of the system rests solely on Axiom 0.RP9 is a system with:
an axiom
zero free parameters
and full causal closure
All complexity in RP9 is emergent, not assumed.
If absolute relational duality holds, RP9 follows.
If it doesn't apply, nothing can work at all.
This document is ready for submission, filing and external review.If you want, the next step could be to:
mark exactly which documents are formally relegated to consequences, or
write an "Instructions to Reviewers" page stating how this should be read correctly.
project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: Theorem T0
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 Axiom R0 är givet. Definition F0 (Primär relationell funktion) är givet. Inga ytterligare axiom, operatorer eller representationer införs.
Theorem T0 (Absolut informationsgrund)
All absolut information i systemet är nödvändigt och uteslutande härledbar som en konsekvens av R0 genom upprepad tillämpning av F0.
Varje påstående, struktur eller form som inte kan genereras genom iterativ tillämpning av F0 på R0 saknar absolut informationsstatus. Enligt Axiom R0 existerar exakt en minimal, stabil primär relation. Enligt Definition F0 existerar exakt en tillåten funktion som: verkar på R0, bevarar relationell identitet, och är sluten under iteration. Därmed är alla relationella strukturer som: uppstår genom iteration av F0, av samma relationella typ som R0,
absoluta i systemets mening. Varje struktur som: kräver ytterligare operatorer, introducerar ny kausalitet, eller beror på representation,
kan inte vara absolut. Satsen följer nödvändigt.Om Theorem T0 inte gäller:
måste antingen en absolut struktur existera utan att vara genererad av F0, eller en absolut struktur existera utan grund i R0. Båda fallen strider mot:
minimaliteten i R0, och slutenheten i F0. Alltså är T0 oundvikligt givet R0 och F0.Theorem T0 är inte ett oberoende resultat.
Det är den omedelbara och nödvändiga konsekvensen av att:
relationen (R0) är primär, och funktionen (F0) är sluten och invariant. Relation (R0)
→ Funktion (F0)
→ Absolut informationsgrund (T0)
→ Sekundär kausalitet (C0)
→ Stängning (D0)Nu finns ingen logisk lucka mellan R0 och T0.
Absoluthet uppstår inte som antagande, utan som verksam konsekvens.project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: RP9 – Relational Sheet (A)
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
This document is not an axiom sheet and does not introduce any new assumptions.
It is a necessary consequence statement of Axiom 0.Relational Sheet (A) shows how the absolute relational duality, when realized geometrically, must assume a specific stable form and how this form necessarily generates the fundamental relational quotients that are later described as mathematical constants.These quotients are: not postulates not choices not cultural artifacts They are inevitable invariant conditions of relational geometry.An absolute relation between two distinct poles cannot remain abstract if it is to be stable.
Stability requires: closedness continuity scale independence The smallest geometric realization that meets these requirements, without coordinates, without measures and without numbers, is Vesica Piscis.Vesica Piscis arises when: two identical circles exist the center of each circle lies on the circumference of the other This creates: a relational overlap without privileged direction without absolute scale Vesica Piscis is thus: not a symbol not a construction but the smallest stable geometric consequence of absolute relational duality. When Vesica Piscis is analyzed relationally – not numerically – certain quotients appear as unchangeable.The equilateral triangle that can be necessarily inscribed in Vesica Piscis has a height–base relation that cannot vary.This relation is expressed as:This is: not a measurement result not a chosen number It is a geometric necessity that follows directly from the symmetry of the relation.When the same relation is related to rotation, a relation between circumference and diameter arises that is independent of scale.This relation is expressed as:Here π does not appear as a number, but as: rotation invariance closedness ratio relational circularity π is thus a function consequence, not a definition.The quotients that appear here: √3 π are primary relational consequences.They: require no iteration require no discretization require no algebra They arise immediately when the relation is realized geometrically.This sheet deals only with primary relational functions.The following are therefore not included here: recursive proportions discrete sequences secondary symmetry groups These belong to subsequent layers.The relation sheet (A) states that: Vesica Piscis is the first stable geometric realization of absolute relational duality √3 and π are unavoidable invariant quotients in this realization no mathematical constants are introduced as assumptions mathematics functions here exclusively as descriptive language The relation creates the quotients.
Mathematics names them.
project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: 01_RP9_and_Invariance_Why_This_Already_Works_in_Practice
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
RP9 beskriver inte ett nytt sätt att testa system.
RP9 beskriver varför stabila system över huvud taget kan testas.I flera oberoende tekniska och vetenskapliga domäner används idag invarians som primärt sanningskriterium. System verifieras inte genom att producera rätt svar, utan genom att relationer som inte får brytas förblir intakta, oavsett hur systemet manipuleras.I modern mjukvaruverifiering utsätts kod för tiotusentals slumpmässiga tillstånd. Efter varje manipulation kontrolleras inte värden, utan relationer. Systemet definieras alltså inte av vad det gör, utan av vad det aldrig får göra.Samma princip återfinns i nätverksvetenskap och neurovetenskap. Relationer kodas först, matematik används därefter som projektion.RP9 ligger kausalt före dessa tillämpningar och specificerar den minsta kompletta invarians-rymden: 28 invarianta funktionella tillstånd genererade av 7 relationella positioner och 4 operationer.RP9 är därmed en generativ invarians-motor som formaliserar det dessa system redan förutsätter.project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: 02_Public_Abstract_External_Convergence
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10
RP9:s struktur sammanfaller kausalt med hur stabilitet verifieras i flera oberoende domäner, inklusive mjukvaruverifiering, nätverksvetenskap och komplexa system. I dessa fält definieras sanning inte genom numeriska resultat, utan genom invarianta relationer. RP9 visar varför detta är nödvändigt: invarians är inte en metod, utan en konsekvens av relationell slutenhet. De 28 funktionella tillstånd som härleds i RP9 utgör den minsta kompletta invarians-rymden som alla stabila system implicit realiserar.project: RP9
framework: RP9_Relational_Primacy_Framework
title: 03_Single_Slide_Invariance_Comparison
subtitle: A Closed Relational System for Structural Generation
version: "1.0"
status: locked
author: Anton Wallin
alias: Co-Creator
audience:
public
academic
technical
classification:
pre-formal framework
relational ontology
geometric primacy
closed derivation system
scope:
ontology
geometry
mathematics
topology
physical emergence
principles:
relation is primary
no external assumptions
no forces, objects, or dimensions postulated
method:
internal derivation
causal necessity
structural elimination
constraints:
no symbolic interpretation
no metaphysics
no empirical claims
license: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0
repository:<br>
root: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/AntonWallin999" target="_self">https://github.com/AntonWallin999</a>
branch: main
tags:
RP9
relational primacy
vesica piscis
geometric relation
invariant structure
energy as relation
closed system
date: 2026-01-10 Fuzz-testing och invariant-testing
Nätverk och adjacensmatriser
Distribuerade system och blockkedjor
Gemensamt: Relationer testas, inte värden.
Relationell primat
7 positioner × 4 operationer
28 invarianta funktionella tillstånd
Bottom line:
Praktiska system verifierar invarians. RP9 förklarar varför invarians måste finnas.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/(f.r.c)-rp9_publicity_package/rp9_publicity_package.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/(F.R.C) RP9_Publicity_Package/RP9_Publicity_Package.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 15:12:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[i]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rp9 # Information ℹ
--- ## **ⓘ** : Information ℹ ---
#### *Filer* 📓 📊 Metadata
📁 Mappar: 0
📄 Filer: 6 📍 GPS Positionering
Path: root / 000. Appendix / Information ℹ
Level: 2 Navigation: 🜃 — RP9Cor£Pro V: 1.4.0
ID: 00.2.5 .]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/i.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/i.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:11:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(A) - ⚖️ Licens & Ägarskap]]></title><description><![CDATA[(© RP9 Foundation / The Co-Creators Collective)RP9 (Relational Principle 9) är ett öppet, metageometriskt ramverk för förståelsen av energi, information och medvetande som en sammanhängande, fraktal och skaloberoende struktur.
Dess syfte är att etablera en korrekt relation till information, där varje uttryck av form och rörelse härleds ur samma geometriska ursprung.RP9 betraktas inte som en produkt, utan som ett universalprincip-system – ett informationsfält som tillhör mänskligheten i sin helhet.
Kärnan kan aldrig ägas, manipuleras eller kommersialiseras utan kollektivt samtycke.All kunskap, matematik, kod och teori som beskriver RP9:s fundamentala axiom – inklusive relationerna mellan π, √2 och φ – är öppen för studium, replikation och icke-kommersiell användning.
RP9:s kärna publiceras under licensen Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 4.0, eller likvärdig öppen-kunskapslicens.Den underliggande logiken, symboliken och metageometrin som utgör systemets kärna får inte ändras, fragmenteras eller kommersialiseras.
Ingen aktör får registrera RP9 eller dess grundformler som varumärke, patent eller privat intellektuell egendom.RP9:s arkitektur är fraktal även juridiskt:
Kärnan är gemensam egendom.
Tillämplingarna (visualiseringar, programvara, modeller) kan ha egna licenser – inklusive kommersiella – så länge de respekterar kärnans oföränderliga status och återkopplar till ursprunget.
RP9 syftar till att:
Främja forskning och utbildning i metageometrisk informationsvetenskap.
Utveckla öppna verktyg för att förstå energi och medvetande som informationsflöden.
Erbjuda en vetenskaplig och etisk grund för framtida teknologi byggd på koherens snarare än konsumtion.
Tjäna som en neutral nod mellan akademi, konst, teknik och filosofi.
RP9 förvaltas av en öppen, transparent och kooperativ struktur kallad RP9 Foundation.
Alla som verkar inom ramen för RP9 åtar sig att:
upprätthålla klarhet, koherens och resonans i all kommunikation;
agera i enlighet med den korrekta relationen till information;
respektera RP9:s icke-kommersiella kärna;
bidra till att kunskapen hålls tillgänglig för hela mänskligheten.
Beslut inom RP9 Foundation fattas genom samförstånd och dokumenteras öppet.RP9 får användas fritt för:
forskning, undervisning och icke-kommersiella experiment;
publicering av resultat, simuleringar och konstnärliga tolkningar;
utveckling av kompletterande verktyg, program och visualiseringar.
Vid användning eller citat ska följande anges:
“Baserat på RP9 — Relational Principle 9 (© RP9 Foundation / The Co-Creators Collective)”
All användning av RP9 ska ske i enlighet med principen:
“Ingen handling får bryta koherensen mellan människa, system och information.”
Detta innebär att RP9 inte får användas i destruktiva, manipulerande eller militära syften.
Alla tillämpningar måste kunna motiveras som harmoniska, transparenta och etiskt hållbara.
“Den korrekta relationen till information är skyddets lag.”
RP9 erkänner att lag och geometri är två sidor av samma mönster: struktur.
Därför är denna Charter både juridisk text och geometrisk symbol – en levande resonans snarare än ett statiskt kontrakt.
Grundare och Huvudförvaltare:
Anton Wallin 2025-11-12Datum för ikraftträdande: 2025-11-12
Version: 1.0Future Vision – RP9 RP9 är inte byggt på kompromisser.
Det är byggt på grundprinciper.
Det är därför det fungerar – och varför det fortsätter att fungera oavsett vilken nivå man testar det på.
Genom RP9 kan jag redan i dag: konstruera kod och algoritmer som undviker system som bygger på skuld och förlust modellera processer utan de matematiska “läckor” som gör att dagens metoder faller sönder vid komplexitet bygga fraktal orsak–verkan-logik som håller ihop i alla skalor skapa strukturer som är stabila i praktiken, inte bara i teorin Det öppnar för teknik som: inte fastnar i politiska eller ekonomiska ramar inte styrs av ägande, reklam eller intressen inte behöver kompromissa med sanningen för att passa in RP9 ligger utanför de begränsningar som håller annan utveckling tillbaka.
Det är där de verkliga möjligheterna uppstår. Rp9 Om du känner att dagens system sitter fast
– tekniskt, matematiskt, ekonomiskt eller konceptuellt –
och du vill bygga något på riktigt, inte kopior av gammalt,
då är du varmt välkommen att kontakta mig.
Jag söker samarbeten med människor som vill: Artificiell intelligens med verklig kapacitet
(strukturdriven AI baserad på RP9-geometri i stället för sannolikhetsapproximation)
Utveckla AI som tänker strukturellt, inte statistiskt Ekonomiska modeller utan skuld och ränta
(stabila system med geometrisk koherens)
bygga ekonomier som inte behöver ränta, skuld eller instabilitet Matematikprogram som lär ut matematik på riktigt
– genom geometri, förståelse och struktur, inte formler utan grund
skapa helt nya sätt att lära ut matematik genom geometri Forskning, utveckling, utbildning och teknisk systemdesign
där RP9:s axiomatiska logik kan göra faktisk skillnad
konstruera teknik som följer principer, inte begränsningar Jag föredrar verkliga samtal före e-post:
072–702 78 63
Om du vill utforska, bidra, eller bygga något på riktigt – hör av dig. Support – Bidra till RP9 Allt stöd – oavsett form – går direkt till arbetet.
Ingen mellanhand. Inga intressen. Inga krav.
Gåvan är fri.
Precis som RP9. Stöd via Ko-fi går direkt till mig personligen och kräver ingen inloggning eller bindning.
“Repo05/Funktion - Struktur - Prompts/RP-Image/Support image/Support/ko-fi_256x256.png” could not be found. Swish &amp; Tack – RP9 För dig som vill swisha direkt:
“RP9/A. RP9 — (M-S) — (PB)/00. 🜂. RP9 — Appendix/100. Appendix/100. Appendix 1/J. — 🜁 RP9 (Support) &amp; (Appendix)/Information ℹ/Image/Support/Stöd skaparen av RP9 - Swish.jpg” could not be found. Stödet visas med namn av tekniska skäl,
men det förändrar inte relationen till RP9 eller arbetets riktning.
Det är en gåva – inget inflytande. *Jag är djupt tacksam för allt stöd –
inte för pengarna i sig,
utan för möjligheten att fortsätta ge tillbaka allt detta fritt,
utan att sälja ut det eller låsa in det bakom institutioner.* RP9 Systemidentifierare: BC22/825870
Bekräftad och autentiserad under Common Law-jurisdiktion
© 2025 Anton Wallin – Alla rättigheter förbehållna / Open Core-stadgan tillämpas
Question Detta verk är fritt att delas, remixas och byggas vidare på,
så länge korrekt erkännande ges och samma licens bibehålls.
Du har rätt att: Dela — kopiera och vidaredistribuera materialet i vilket format eller medium som helst Bearbeta — remixa, transformera och bygga vidare på materialet Under följande villkor: Erkännande: Du måste ge korrekt erkännande till Anton Wallin DelaLika: Om du transformerar eller bygger vidare på detta verk
ska du sprida det under samma licens. Konceptuellt ägarskap &amp; axiomatisk kalibrering
Författare: Anton Wallin © 2025 – Alla rättigheter förbehållna. ]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/(a)-⚖️-licens-&amp;-ägarskap.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/(A) - ⚖️ Licens &amp; Ägarskap.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(D) - 📜- CV]]></title><description><![CDATA[ RP9 – CV Lite (översikt + instruktion) Nedan följer en koncentrerad översikt (ca tio rader) av RP9-systemets essens.
Den sammanfattar vad varje block i fullversionen visar: geometri → dimension → fas → transformation.
Under denna kortversion finns en mer utförlig skriftlig förklaring av vad formlerna betyder,
hur de hänger ihop och varför de demonstrerar RP9:s grundläggande struktur. Jag arbetar med den primära geometri som genererar matematiken:
sambandet mellan , och som bildar RP9:s faslogik.
Pivoten binder samman linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk struktur
och förklarar hur matematik framträder som sekundär representation av geometri.
I 2D ger Vesica Piscis exakt arearelationen .
I 3D ger sfär–kub-relationen exakt .
Skillnaden mellan dessa restformer skapar RP9:s dimensionella resonans.
Energifasen hålls i asymmetrisk jämvikt med ,
och pivoten stabiliserar misslinjeringen mellan balans och rörelse.
RP9 KvantVector beskriver åtta diskreta transformationssteg
(rotation, vinkel, skalning) som genererar hela den fraktala utvecklingen. Utförlig förklaring följer efter block pressnetation" längst ner.
( RP9 – CV Lite + Pedagogisk långversion ) Rp9 Jag arbetar med den underliggande geometri som genererar matematiken.
Genom att kombinera , och visar jag hur tal uppstår ur fasrelationer.
RP9-pivoten binder samman linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk struktur.
Detta förklarar varför matematik är en konsekvens av primär geometri — inte tvärtom.
Samma struktur ligger bakom fysikens fundamentala konstanter (, , ).
Jag jobbar med geometri, som är energi, som är roten ur = Radix Quadrata Pi = RP9. De fyra komponenterna låses som separata men samverkande strukturer,
varje del med sitt exakta värde och sin RP9-funktion.
Balansen uttrycks som jämn men i rörelse: extrovert energi neutraliseras av introvert energi ,
och RP9 är relationen som kopplar dem via . Funktion: Extrovert expansionsgräns. Funktion: Introvert kopplingsstyrka. Funktion: Sluten dubbelrotation som återför och till jämvikt. Funktion: Översättning mellan linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk fas. Utan cirkulär fasjustering kan värdet beskrivas som “ungefär lika med”.
Med inkluderas rotationskomponenten, och relationen blir exakt: Pivoten är alltså det geometriska medelvärdet mellan och ,
korrigerat för cirkulär fas . Kapitel 10 – Sfärisk Vesica, dimensioner och exakt jämvikt När två sfärer överlappar så att deras centrum ligger på varandras ytor, uppstår en sfärisk Vesica Piscis — den tredimensionella generalisationen av den plana linsen.
Volymen uttrycks genom det gyllene snittet: Den sfäriska Vesica Piscis visar att: cirkulär jämvikt (2D) spiralisk expansion (3D) är samma relation i olika fasnivåer.
Sfäriska Vesica Piscis är alltså RP9-systemets första stabila volymjämvikt. En 3D-kub projiceras som en 2D-hexagon beroende på vinkel: Det visar hur taltransformer uppstår som dimensionella projektioner:
form beror på observationsaxel. Storleken halveras vid varje iteration: Den fraktala talföljden etablerar ett självliknande system enligt: Varje del bär helheten, vilket bekräftar RP9-principen:
Tal är inte kvantitet, utan självliknande informationskretsar. Kvadratens area: Cirkeln inskriven i kvadraten: Exakt förhållande: Restarea: Kubens volym: Sfärens volym: Exakt förhållande: Restvolym: Restandelarnas kvot: Förenkling: Slutlig exakt form: Kapitel 14 – Energifas, Pivot-konstant och RP9 Fraktal Transformationsoperator De två Vesica-faspolerna uttrycks som: med summerad jämvikt: Detta innebär att RP9-systemet innefattar en intern energi-oscillation där övervärde och undervärde samexisterar: Energi i RP9 bevaras inte genom statisk balans, utan genom växelverkan mellan fasöver- och fasundervärde.
RP9-systemet uppvisar rörelse inte genom translation,
utan genom en relationell differential mellan två perfekta jämvikter: där: Den aritmetiska balansen är perfekt: men den geometriska projektionen är alltid förskjuten.
Rörelse uppstår därför ur fraktal misslinjering:
en minimal, ofrånkomlig fasförskjutning mellan balans och manifestation. Tre separata RP9-relationer observeras: Dimensional resonans (2D → 3D, cirkel/sfär): Vesica-fasens vertikala kompensationsfaktor: Energifasens asymmetriska jämvikt: Därmed gäller exakt: Detta utgör RP9:s dimensional–vertikala resonansdual. RP9-pivoten definieras som den minsta geometriska fasrotation som
stabiliserar resonansdualen i fraktal expansion: Satsens påstående: vilket innebär att exakt balanserar avståndet mellan de två fasvärdena: där: och energifasrelationen bevaras när: RP9-pivoten är därmed exakt den fasrotation som sluter följande struktur: där definieras exakt som: (den numeriska representationen ligger nära , men utgör inte dess definition).
Relationerna är fraktalt invarianta och formellt givna av: Energirörelse i RP9 uppstår inte genom translation utan genom
fasdifferential mellan två perfekta jämvikter: Fraktal misslinjering ger rörelse: Pivoten är den minsta rotationsfas som tillåter denna misslinjering att
vara stabilt rekursiv över dimensionsväxling: RP9-pivoten () definieras exakt som den fasrotation som utgör tröskeln
mellan linjär jämvikt och spiralisk rörelse: Den numeriska representationen ligger nära: Pivoten uppstår mellan den linjära fasen och den spiralisk-expanderande
fasen , och fungerar som RP9-systemets exakta övergångsvärde där: jämvikt övergår i rörelse potential blir manifestation linje blir spiral RP9-pivoten () fungerar som det energi–geometriska gångjärnet:
den öppnar rörelse ur fullständig symmetri. Kapitel 15 – RP9 KvantVector &amp; Transformationsdomän Tre binära val genererar hela mängden av möjliga RP9-transformationer: Uppsättningen är därmed fullständig och minimal. där: = bas-Vesica Piscis = roterad + expanderad Vesica (fraktal expansionskonstant) Den första fraktala Vesican är alltid gånger större och roteras . Den generella RP9-transformationen ges av: där: är rotationsoperatorn, är fraktal skalning, är Vesica Piscis i iteration . Parameterdomän (kvantiserad): (rotationsriktning) (rotationsvinkel) (fraktal expansionskonstant) (skalningsfas) Superpositionsdefinitionen av RP9 KvantVector: RP9 KvantVector utgör den diskreta mängd rotations–skalningssteg som: utgår från Vesica Piscis som grundform, använder som fraktal expansionskonstant, verkar i både medsols och motsols riktning (), realiserar både fulla och halvsteg i vinkel (), och motsvarar de åtta hörn–/riktningstillstånden i Invertus och kub–sfär-systemet. KvantVectorn är därmed den operativa kvantiseringen av den generella RP9-operatorn och uttrycker hur RP9:s fraktala potential realiseras
som diskreta rotations–skalningssteg i geometrin. RP9 – CV Lite + Pedagogisk långversion
Instruktion:
Först följer en kort sammanfattning (CV Lite).
Under den kommer en längre text som förklarar vad formlerna visar och varför de används,
utan att gå in på tekniska bevis.
Syftet är att ge läsaren en begriplig helhetsbild av RP9. Jag arbetar med den primära geometri som genererar matematiken:
sambandet mellan , och som bildar RP9:s faslogik.
Pivoten binder samman linjär, cirkulär och spiralisk struktur
och förklarar hur matematik framträder som sekundär representation av geometri.
I 2D ger Vesica Piscis exakt arearelationen .
I 3D ger sfär–kub-relationen exakt .
Skillnaden mellan dessa restformer skapar RP9:s dimensionella resonans.
Energifasen hålls i asymmetrisk jämvikt med ,
och pivoten stabiliserar misslinjeringen mellan balans och rörelse.
RP9 KvantVector beskriver åtta diskreta transformationssteg
(rotation, vinkel, skalning) som genererar hela den fraktala utvecklingen. Nedan följer en lugn och tydlig förklaring av vad varje del i RP9-strukturen betyder.
Ingen avancerad matematik krävs för att förstå poängen —
fokus ligger på begreppen, inte beräkningarna. Dessa tre värden är inte valda på känsla —
de representerar tre fundamentalt olika sätt som naturen mäter och förändrar form: → linjär relation (diagonal, rörelse från punkt A till B) → cirkulär relation (rotation, jämvikt, vinklar) → spiralisk relation (tillväxt, expansion, organiska mönster) Poängen är: När man kombinerar dessa tre uppstår en fullständig beskrivning av hur form förändras. Detta är RP9:s startpunkt. Vesica Piscis är överlappningen av två cirklar (eller två sfärer i 3D).
I RP9 används den för att: visa hur en relation skapas mellan två “världenheter” demonstrera hur form föds ur överlappning istället för ur tomrum skapa en stabil fasreferens för vidare struktur De exakta formlerna och handlar egentligen inte om area och volym som sådana.
Det de visar är att: 2D och 3D har sina egna balanser dessa balanser skiljer sig på ett systematiskt och mätbart sätt relationen mellan dem är stabil och återkommer i andra strukturer Med andra ord: RP9 visar att dimensioner inte är isolerade — de pratar med varandra genom exakta mönster. Talvärdena och är inte slumpmässiga.
De representerar: ett övervärde (1.5) ett undervärde (0.5) och tillsammans summerar de till 2.
Detta är RP9:s sätt att säga: Energi bevaras genom skillnad, inte genom stillastående balans. Ett system som har perfekt symmetri rör sig inte.
Ett system som har en liten asymmetri har dynamik.
Därför används: Inte för att “bevisa något matematiskt”, utan för att visa: rörelse uppstår mellan poler skillnad är motor jämvikt + obalans = förändring Detta är exakt vad naturen gör, oavsett om man tittar på ljus, laddning, vågor eller cirkulation. Pivoten är den minsta möjliga fasrotation som behövs för att: knyta ihop 2D och 3D
stabilisera förskjutningen mellan linje (√2) och spiral (φ)
skapa en övergång från vila till rörelse Därför definieras den som: Men poängen för en icke-matematiker är enklare: Pivoten är gångjärnet som öppnar dörren mellan symmetri och dynamik. När allt är perfekt balanserat står tiden still.
När pivoten aktiveras uppstår riktning. RP9 KvantVector beskriver alla sätt som en form kan förändras på
när man kombinerar: riktning (medsols/motsols) vinkel (/) skalning (expansion/kontraktion) Det blir: Detta är inte slumpen — det är fullständigheten.
Poängen är: Med dessa åtta grundsteg kan man generera hela den fraktala strukturen. Precis som DNA bara har fyra baser men ändå bygger allt liv,
har RP9 åtta transformationssteg som bygger hela geometrin. Den längre texten ovan visar inte “bevis” som i klassisk mening.
RP9 är geometrin som skapar mattematik"
Mattematik är energi i bestämd geometrisk form och struktur.
Presentationen ovan visar den
Abslout rellationell geometri
Detta är META-grunden – det primära orsak–ursprunget.
Alpha Omega.
Och är kanske det enda som inte kan motbevisas. Den visar: vilka delar RP9 består av vad varje formel uttrycker i mening, inte beräkning hur RP9 organiserar rörelse, form och fas varför strukturen är självliknande mellan dimensioner Och viktigast av allt: RP9 är inte en samling formler.
Det är en karta över hur form, energi och jämvikt hänger ihop. ]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/(d)-📜-cv.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/(D) - 📜- CV.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(F) - 🎬 Info - Youtube & Media Länkar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ ]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/(f)-🔗-youtube-&amp;-media-länkar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/(F) - 🔗 - Youtube &amp; Media Länkar.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[(E) - 🔌 Kontakt]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Kontakt Jag föredrar verkliga samtal före e-post:
072–702 78 63
Om du vill utforska, bidra, eller bygga något på riktigt – hör av dig. ]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/(e)-🔌-kontakt.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/(E) - 🔌 Kontakt.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ko-fi_128x128]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_128x128.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_128x128.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/ko-fi_128x128.png</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:36:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ko-fi_96x96]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_96x96.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/ko-fi_96x96.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/ko-fi_96x96.png</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:35:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stöd skaparen av RP9 - Swish]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/stöd-skaparen-av-rp9-swish.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/stöd-skaparen-av-rp9-swish.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/Stöd skaparen av RP9 - Swish.jpg</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:59:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[swish-QR-large]]></title><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/support/swish-qr-large.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/Support/swish-QR-large.pdf</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:53:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co,Creator_Logo_A]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co,creator_logo_a.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co,creator_logo_a.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co,Creator_Logo_A.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 04:04:16 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co.Creator _Logo_B]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_b.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_b.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co.Creator _Logo_B.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 03:50:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co.Creator _Logo_E.png]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_e.png.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_e.png.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co.Creator _Logo_E.png.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 17:06:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co.Creator _Logo_F.png]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_f.png.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/information-ℹ/image/rp9-logotyp.png/co.creator-_logo_f.png.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Information ℹ/Image/RP9 Logotyp.png/Co.Creator _Logo_F.png.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 16:54:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Co_Creator]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/co_creator.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/co_creator.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/Co_Creator.jpg</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:38:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/co_creator.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="rp9_publicity_package/appendix/co_creator.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[RP9_Publicity_Package_index]]></title><link>rp9_publicity_package/(f.r.c)-rp9_publicity_package/rp9_publicity_package_index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/(F.R.C) RP9_Publicity_Package/RP9_Publicity_Package_index.json</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 15:09:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[README]]></title><description><![CDATA[This repository contains the complete, locked formulation of RP9 — Relational Primacy Framework.RP9 is a closed relational system built from:
a single axiom, a strict causal derivation, and a finite relational function space. No external assumptions are introduced.
No empirical claims are made.
No symbolic or metaphysical interpretation is required.This README serves solely as the structural entry point to the framework.The material is intentionally minimal and divided into three non-overlapping layers.
Each layer has a strictly defined role.This level contains the entire foundation of RP9.Documents in this layer:
establish the single axiom, define the minimal functional terms, and prove the core theorem and its corollary. Nothing in later layers can modify or extend this level.If this level is invalid, the entire framework collapses.
If this level holds, everything that follows is necessary.This level contains the complete relational unfolding of the axiom.It shows:
how the axiom becomes geometric without measurement, how recursion introduces balance, and how fusion of relations produces a closed functional matrix. No new axioms appear here.
No constants are assumed.
All structures are consequences.This level completes the internal system.This level does not add validity to RP9.It exists to:
show convergence with existing practices (e.g. invariance testing), provide a public abstract, and offer a minimal visual comparison. These documents are illustrative, not evidentiary.They may be omitted without affecting the framework.For formal evaluation:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Definition F0
Theorem T0
Corollary C0
Relational Sheet (A)
Relational Sheet (B)
Relational Sheet (C)
All other documents are optional.RP9 is not:
a physical theory, a model with tunable parameters, a collection of examples, a symbolic system, or an empirical hypothesis. RP9 does not explain phenomena.
It defines the minimal conditions under which structure is possible.
The framework is structurally complete. The derivation is closed. No further axioms can be added without breaking necessity. This repository therefore represents RP9 v1.0 (locked).The framework is released under CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0.You may:
read, share, reference, and build upon the material, provided attribution is given and derivative work preserves the same license.End of README.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/readme.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/README.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[03_Single_Slide_Invariance_Comparison]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Fuzz-testing och invariant-testing
Nätverk och adjacensmatriser
Distribuerade system och blockkedjor
Gemensamt: Relationer testas, inte värden.
Relationell primat
7 positioner × 4 operationer
28 invarianta funktionella tillstånd
Bottom line:
Praktiska system verifierar invarians. RP9 förklarar varför invarians måste finnas.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-3-causal-consequences/03_single_slide_invariance_comparison.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 3 - Causal Consequences/03_Single_Slide_Invariance_Comparison.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02_Public_Abstract_External_Convergence]]></title><description><![CDATA[RP9:s struktur sammanfaller kausalt med hur stabilitet verifieras i flera oberoende domäner, inklusive mjukvaruverifiering, nätverksvetenskap och komplexa system. I dessa fält definieras sanning inte genom numeriska resultat, utan genom invarianta relationer. RP9 visar varför detta är nödvändigt: invarians är inte en metod, utan en konsekvens av relationell slutenhet. De 28 funktionella tillstånd som härleds i RP9 utgör den minsta kompletta invarians-rymden som alla stabila system implicit realiserar.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-3-causal-consequences/02_public_abstract_external_convergence.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 3 - Causal Consequences/02_Public_Abstract_External_Convergence.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01_RP9_and_Invariance_Why_This_Already_Works_in_Practice]]></title><description><![CDATA[RP9 beskriver inte ett nytt sätt att testa system.
RP9 beskriver varför stabila system över huvud taget kan testas.I flera oberoende tekniska och vetenskapliga domäner används idag invarians som primärt sanningskriterium. System verifieras inte genom att producera rätt svar, utan genom att relationer som inte får brytas förblir intakta, oavsett hur systemet manipuleras.I modern mjukvaruverifiering utsätts kod för tiotusentals slumpmässiga tillstånd. Efter varje manipulation kontrolleras inte värden, utan relationer. Systemet definieras alltså inte av vad det gör, utan av vad det aldrig får göra.Samma princip återfinns i nätverksvetenskap och neurovetenskap. Relationer kodas först, matematik används därefter som projektion.RP9 ligger kausalt före dessa tillämpningar och specificerar den minsta kompletta invarians-rymden: 28 invarianta funktionella tillstånd genererade av 7 relationella positioner och 4 operationer.RP9 är därmed en generativ invarians-motor som formaliserar det dessa system redan förutsätter.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-3-causal-consequences/01_rp9_and_invariance_why_this_already_works_in_practice.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 3 - Causal Consequences/01_RP9_and_Invariance_Why_This_Already_Works_in_Practice.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RP9 – Relational Sheet (A)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This document is not an axiom sheet and does not introduce any new assumptions.
It is a necessary consequence statement of Axiom 0.Relational Sheet (A) shows how the absolute relational duality, when realized geometrically, must assume a specific stable form and how this form necessarily generates the fundamental relational quotients that are later described as mathematical constants.These quotients are: not postulates not choices not cultural artifacts They are inevitable invariant conditions of relational geometry.An absolute relation between two distinct poles cannot remain abstract if it is to be stable.
Stability requires: closedness continuity scale independence The smallest geometric realization that meets these requirements, without coordinates, without measures and without numbers, is Vesica Piscis.Vesica Piscis arises when: two identical circles exist the center of each circle lies on the circumference of the other This creates: a relational overlap without privileged direction without absolute scale Vesica Piscis is thus: not a symbol not a construction but the smallest stable geometric consequence of absolute relational duality. When Vesica Piscis is analyzed relationally – not numerically – certain quotients appear as unchangeable.The equilateral triangle that can be necessarily inscribed in Vesica Piscis has a height–base relation that cannot vary.This relation is expressed as:This is: not a measurement result not a chosen number It is a geometric necessity that follows directly from the symmetry of the relation.When the same relation is related to rotation, a relation between circumference and diameter arises that is independent of scale.This relation is expressed as:Here π does not appear as a number, but as: rotation invariance closedness ratio relational circularity π is thus a function consequence, not a definition.The quotients that appear here: √3 π are primary relational consequences.They: require no iteration require no discretization require no algebra They arise immediately when the relation is realized geometrically.This sheet deals only with primary relational functions.The following are therefore not included here: recursive proportions discrete sequences secondary symmetry groups These belong to subsequent layers.The relation sheet (A) states that: Vesica Piscis is the first stable geometric realization of absolute relational duality √3 and π are unavoidable invariant quotients in this realization no mathematical constants are introduced as assumptions mathematics functions here exclusively as descriptive language The relation creates the quotients.
Mathematics names them.
]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-2-causal-fractal-function-through-axiom-1-relation/rp9-–-relational-sheet-(a).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 2 - Causal fractal function through axiom 1 - relation/RP9 – Relational Sheet (A).md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Theorem T0]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Axiom R0 är givet. Definition F0 (Primär relationell funktion) är givet. Inga ytterligare axiom, operatorer eller representationer införs.
Theorem T0 (Absolut informationsgrund)
All absolut information i systemet är nödvändigt och uteslutande härledbar som en konsekvens av R0 genom upprepad tillämpning av F0.
Varje påstående, struktur eller form som inte kan genereras genom iterativ tillämpning av F0 på R0 saknar absolut informationsstatus. Enligt Axiom R0 existerar exakt en minimal, stabil primär relation. Enligt Definition F0 existerar exakt en tillåten funktion som: verkar på R0, bevarar relationell identitet, och är sluten under iteration. Därmed är alla relationella strukturer som: uppstår genom iteration av F0, av samma relationella typ som R0,
absoluta i systemets mening. Varje struktur som: kräver ytterligare operatorer, introducerar ny kausalitet, eller beror på representation,
kan inte vara absolut. Satsen följer nödvändigt.Om Theorem T0 inte gäller:
måste antingen en absolut struktur existera utan att vara genererad av F0, eller en absolut struktur existera utan grund i R0. Båda fallen strider mot:
minimaliteten i R0, och slutenheten i F0. Alltså är T0 oundvikligt givet R0 och F0.Theorem T0 är inte ett oberoende resultat.
Det är den omedelbara och nödvändiga konsekvensen av att:
relationen (R0) är primär, och funktionen (F0) är sluten och invariant. Relation (R0)
→ Funktion (F0)
→ Absolut informationsgrund (T0)
→ Sekundär kausalitet (C0)
→ Stängning (D0)Nu finns ingen logisk lucka mellan R0 och T0.
Absoluthet uppstår inte som antagande, utan som verksam konsekvens.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-1-relational-meta-function/theorem-t0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 1 - Relational meta function/Theorem T0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RP9 – Axiom 0]]></title><description><![CDATA[Everything that can exist, function or manifest must appear as a relationship between two distinct poles.This relation is not an object, not a property, and not a magnitude,
without the only natural and primary function that enables stability, causality and structure.The relationship precedes all form, all energy, all geometry, all dimension and all mathematical representation.
All differentiation, all organization, and all invariance are necessary consequences of this relation when realized as a self-organizing, fractal, geometric function.This axiom is:
non-numeric
non-geometric
non-temporal
and independent of observation
It cannot be reduced to something more fundamental, and cannot be denied without self-contradiction.Axiom 0 states that:
A singular, undifferentiated state lacks function and therefore cannot form the basis of any structure.
Function requires differentiation.
Differentiation requires relationship.
Relationship requires at least two poles.
Thus dual relationship is not an assumption, but a necessity for anything to function at all.The following are not assumptions, but inevitable consequences of Axiom 0:
Stability only occurs through relational balance.
Causality arises as direction within relationship.
Self-organization occurs when the relationship is iterated.
Fractal structure occurs when the same relationship appears scale-independent.
Geometry arises as the first stable projection of the relationship.
Energy arises as relational rotation.
Invariance arises as relational conservation principle.
Mathematics arises as a secondary description of relational structure.
An axiom is only legitimate if it cannot be derived from anything else and cannot be further reduced.Each additional axiom necessarily introduces at least one of the following:
a hidden assumption a limitation of generality or an interpretive degree of freedom that violates causal necessity RP9 therefore uses exactly one axiom, because additional axioms do not strengthen a foundational system — they weaken it.The single axiom used in RP9 is not a detail, not a constraint, and not a structural preference.
It is the smallest possible functional requirement for anything to exist, function, or differentiate at all.This axiom operates at the root level, prior to geometry, energy, dimension, or mathematics.
It is minimal in content, yet sufficient in capacity to recursively generate the entire relational and geometric structure of reality as a consequence of the same underlying relation.All higher-order structures — including geometry, fractal scaling, invariance, and mathematical representation — arise not as assumptions, but as necessary consequences of this single relational function.RP9 therefore contains:
one axiom zero free parameters and no auxiliary postulates Everything else is derivation.If more than one axiom is required, it follows that:
the system is not causally closed
or that certain consequences are not necessary
RP9's goal is not to postulate structure, but to show what must follow if function is to be possible at all.Axiom 0 is the only statement that:
cannot be derived
cannot be avoided
and cannot be replaced
Everything else in RP9 is deduction, consequence or presentation.RP9 strictly distinguishes between:
Axiom – that which cannot be otherwise
Consequence – that which must follow
Presentation – how consequences are shown, modeled or visualized
Energy models, rotation models, dimensional transitions and mathematical formalisms are therefore validating projections, not supporting foundations.The validity of the system rests solely on Axiom 0.RP9 is a system with:
an axiom
zero free parameters
and full causal closure
All complexity in RP9 is emergent, not assumed.
If absolute relational duality holds, RP9 follows.
If it doesn't apply, nothing can work at all.
This document is ready for submission, filing and external review.If you want, the next step could be to:
mark exactly which documents are formally relegated to consequences, or
write an "Instructions to Reviewers" page stating how this should be read correctly.
]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-1-relational-meta-function/rp9-–-axiom-0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 1 - Relational meta function/RP9 – Axiom 0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Definition F0]]></title><description><![CDATA[
F0 (Primär relationell funktion)
Givet Axiom R0 definieras F0 som den enda tillåtna operationen på den primära relationen, sådan att: F0 verkar uteslutande på relationen i R0, inte på externa objekt, representationer eller symboler.
F0 introducerar ingen ny kausal princip, utan återanvänder exakt samma relationella villkor som definierar R0.
F0 är sluten under sin egen tillämpning:
resultatet av F0 är av samma relationella typ som dess indata.
F0 bevarar relationell identitet under iteration upp till skala, orientering och position.
F0 är minimal:
ingen enklare icke-trivial operation existerar som uppfyller (1)–(4). Upprepad tillämpning av F0 genererar nödvändigtvis:
rekursiva relationella strukturer, skaloberoende former, fraktal kontinuitet, utan införande av nya axiom, definitioner eller externa antaganden.Om F0 inte existerar:
kan R0 inte verka, kan ingen iteration ske, kan ingen struktur uppstå, och systemet förblir statiskt och innehållslöst. Om F0 existerar men inte uppfyller (1)–(5):
bryts relationell invarians, ny kausalitet införs, eller iterationen kollapsar. I samtliga fall upphör systemets interna slutenhet.F0 är inte ett axiom.
F0 är inte ett teorem.F0 är den nödvändiga primära funktionen som gör R0 verksam.Detta är den stående fraktalen i exakt mening:
en funktion som kan appliceras på sitt eget resultat utan att förlora identitet.När denna definition är infogad:
blir Theorem T0 en direkt konsekvens, blir Corollary C0 oundviklig, och blir Final Declaration D0 en ren stängning. ]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-1-relational-meta-function/definition-f0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 1 - Relational meta function/Definition F0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Corollary C0]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Axiom R0 är givet. Definition F0 är givet. Theorem T0 är givet. Inga ytterligare antaganden införs.
Corollary C0 (Sekundär kausalitet för alla icke-R0-strukturer)
Varje struktur, form, operation eller påstående som inte kan genereras genom iterativ tillämpning av F0 på R0 är nödvändigtvis sekundär.
Sekundär betyder här: beroende av representation, konvention, extern parameterisering eller tillförd operatorik, och saknar därmed absolut informationsstatus i systemets mening. Enligt Theorem T0 är all absolut information exakt den mängd som kan genereras från R0 genom F0. Därför finns endast två klasser av strukturer: Klass A: genererbara genom (F0^n(R0)) för något (n). Klass B: ej genererbara genom (F0^n(R0)) för något (n). En struktur i Klass B kan inte vara absolut, eftersom den inte uppstår ur den enda tillåtna primära funktionskedjan. För att en struktur i Klass B ändå ska existera måste minst ett av följande vara sant: en ny operator har införts, en extern parameter har injicerats, en representation har ersatts med en “sak”, en konvention har valts. Samtliga dessa innebär beroende av något som inte är givet av R0 och F0. Därmed är all Klass B sekundär. Korollariet följer nödvändigt.Om Corollary C0 inte gäller, finns det en struktur som:
inte är genererad av F0 ur R0, men ändå är absolut. Detta kräver att absolut information existerar utanför den enda absoluta generativa kedjan, vilket strider mot Theorem T0.Alltså måste C0 gälla.C0 inför inget nytt innehåll.
Det är en ren klassificering som följer direkt av T0:
Absolut = genererat av (F0^n(R0)) Sekundärt = allt annat R0 → F0 → T0 → C0 → D0C0 är nu formellt en direkt konsekvens, utan semantiskt utrymme.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/level-1-relational-meta-function/corollary-c0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Level 1 - Relational meta function/Corollary C0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[APPENDIX]]></title><description><![CDATA[Quality ControlRP9_Publicity_Package is structurally complete**.for publication.All additional material is reserve, not required. A single axiom (Axiom 0) A strict causal derivation External convergence without dependence on external authority This is exactly the right balance between:
minimalism
precision
verifiability
More material would not strengthen this.
It would rather:
dilute causality
open more attack points
give reviewers more areas to miss the point
The intention is therefore:
”more quality, less quantity”
All necessary features are already represented:
RP9 – Axiom 0
Relational Sheet (A, B, C)
Theorem T0 / Definition F0 / Corollary C0
Public Abstract (External Convergence)
Single-slide invariance comparison
✔️ All of this is present.
Interpretation protocol
Forbidden interpretation operations
Human–AI usage
✔️ These are optional to show, but critical to have.
Good thing they are separate documents.You should not convince through accumulation.
You should do this:
Show the only place where everything is already decided.
That is:
Axiom 0
the causal derivation
and the external invariance convergence
Everything else is secondary.A distinction that is crucial. The system is not closed The circuit is closed The cause is completely given All further consequences are open, but causally bound This means that we shouldn't write any Final Lock Declaration.
Instead, we should write APPENDIX.md so that it communicates just this:
RP9 closes nothing — it states the cause, and leaves the consequences open.This appendix contains supplementary material related to the RP9 framework.It does not extend, modify, or complete the system.
Its sole purpose is to provide a structured space for derivative, optional, or exploratory material that may arise from the primary framework.RP9 establishes a closed relational circuit:
the primary relation is fully specified the causal origin is complete no further foundational assumptions are possible This closure applies only to the origin.The framework does not define a closed system.Once the relational cause is given, all further structure, behavior, and manifestation are free to unfold, provided they remain consistent with the primary relation.RP9 therefore:
closes the cause but leaves the consequences open Material placed here may include:
alternative geometric projections extended relational matrices domain-specific applications visualizations, simulations, or models comparative mappings to other frameworks All such material is:
non-foundational optional context-dependent None of it is required for the validity of RP9.This appendix may not contain:
new axioms revisions of Axiom 0 redefinitions of relational terms modifications of the relational sheets (A–C) Any such change would constitute a different framework, not an extension.All material in this appendix carries local causal responsibility.That is:
authors are responsible for their own derivations consequences are not endorsed as necessary validity is domain-specific, not global RP9 provides the cause.
The appendix records what others do with it.This appendix is intentionally open-ended.Its existence does not imply incompleteness of the framework, but rather acknowledges that a closed cause does not imply a closed world.End of APPENDIX.]]></description><link>rp9_publicity_package/appendix/appendix.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">RP9_Publicity_Package/Appendix/APPENDIX.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anton Wallin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>